I was 86% correct on accurately
我仅凭睡眠时间就能准确
predicting when an NBA team will be at
预测NBA球队何时
highest risk of losing strictly based on
最有可能输球，准确率高达86%。
the sleep oh gosh yes and just 15 or 30
天哪，真的！仅仅15到30
minutes can make a difference so let's
分钟的睡眠就能产生巨大影响。所以，让我们
dive into just some very practical
深入探讨一些
strategies to get the best sleep
获得最佳睡眠的实用策略。Sharim
possible Dr sharim ma is a renowned
Ma博士是一位著名的
sleep doctor and performance expert
睡眠医生和运动表现专家，
whose sleep optimization research has
他的睡眠优化研究不仅
enhanced the careers of CEOs as well as
提升了CEO的职业生涯，也帮助了
athletes in the NFL MLB and Formula 1
NFL、MLB和F1的运动员，
and has provided lifechanging expertise
并为Under Armour和谷歌等公司提供了改变人生的专业知识。
for my Elite athletes that I work with
对于我合作的精英运动员来说，
sufficient sleep it's a game Cher for
充足的睡眠至关重要。
example we saw 12% faster Reaction Time
例如，我们发现，睡眠充足后，他们的反应时间提高了12%，
a 9% Improvement in free throws and a 4%
罚球命中率提高了9%，
increase in Faster Sprint time and when
冲刺速度提高了4%。当
you experience what it feels like to be
你体验到睡眠充足的感觉时，
well rested you never want to go back
你绝对不想再回到
getting insufficient sleep and it
睡眠不足的状态。睡眠提升不必如此显著，
doesn't have to be these big jumps I'd
我很
love to dig into that okay so i' have a
乐意深入探讨这一点。好的，我
shower then I get straight into bed
洗完澡就直接上床睡觉，这样
after is that good or bad tweak the
好还是不好？调整一下
timing of your shower and your hot bath
淋浴和泡热水澡的时间，最好控制在
to just an hour or two before bed it's
一两个小时以内。 睡前
hard to grasp how much of a difference
很难想象
this can make in your life what about
这会对你的生活产生多大的影响。那么
sex does it have an impact on your sleep
性生活呢？它会影响睡眠吗？
okay so is there anything that I can eat
好吧，那么有没有什么东西可以在睡前吃，既
before bed that won't disrupt my sleep
不会影响睡眠，
but will get rid of The Hunger there's a
又能消除饥饿感呢？比如
pre-sleep meal for example cereal and
睡前吃点东西，像麦片加
milk cereal and the reason why is
牛奶之类的。原因很简单。
because and then I read this fascinating
然后我读到一个很有意思的
word nappuccino yes this is a useful
词——纳布奇诺（Nappuccino）。
tool if you're a working professional
如果你是职场人士，
and you need a little boost and
需要提神醒脑、提高工作
alertness and performance what you do is
效率，纳布奇诺是个不错的选择。DI
the DI of AO raffle is about to close
of AO 的抽奖活动即将结束。在
before we hit 7 million subscribers
我们达到 700 万订阅用户之前（
which is probably going to be in a
可能就在几天后），所有订阅 DI of 的人都将自动参与
in the raffle and on the day we hit 7
抽奖。在我们达到 700 万订阅用户当天，
million subscribers we are giving away a
我们将送出
lot of money can't buy prizes to all of
许多千金难买的奖品。
you so hit the Subscribe button get in
所以，点击订阅按钮，在
before 7 million and I'll announce the
700 万订阅用户之前加入我们吧！达到 700 万订阅用户后，我会
prizes and the winners in the comments
在下面的评论区公布奖品和获奖者名单。
[Music]
[音乐]
Dr M what is it you do and why is it so
Dr M，这是什么？ 你会这么做，而且为什么
important in your mind that you do
在你看来它如此重要？
it great question so I am a sleep
问得好。我是一名睡眠
physician um but I spend a lot of my
医生，但我投入了大量的
time and career trying to educate and
时间和精力来教育
and advocate for people to prioritize
和倡导人们重视
sleep right this fascinating process
睡眠。睡眠是一个奇妙的过程，
that each of us does every single night
我们每个人每晚都在经历，可以
and arguably is about a third of our
说它占据了我们
lives but many individuals don't do this
生命的三分之一。但很多人睡眠质量不好，
very well or they you know sacrifice it
或者他们牺牲睡眠，
and overlook this area I very much
忽视睡眠。我
believe if you don't sleep your best you
坚信，如果你睡眠不足，你就不会处于
will not be your best or counter to that
最佳状态；反之亦然，
is if you your if your sleep is best
如果你睡眠充足，
you'll be at your best and what that
你就会处于最佳状态。
means if I unpack that a little bit more
如果我再详细解释一下，这意味着
is we often are sacrificing our sleep
我们经常牺牲睡眠，睡眠
we're underslept we often don't have
不足，
good quality sleep it we're very
睡眠质量差，我们对
reactive to our sleep at night time and
夜间睡眠非常敏感，而且
the end of the day when we wrap
一天结束时，当我们结束
everything up um and that's arguably not
所有事情后，睡眠往往是我们最后才会想到的事情。这无疑会影响我们
we can be in the following day right and
第二天的状态。
for my Elite athletes that I work with
对于我合作的精英运动员来说，
when you actually get sufficient sleep
当你真正获得充足的睡眠时，你会发现睡眠质量至关重要。 充足的睡眠能让
you have practices that you plan into
你养成一些
your day and you actually are more
日常习惯，让你在生活中更加
proactive with that it can be a game
积极主动。对一些人来说，睡眠充足，比如
performance on the field that can be the
在球场上，就能提高
throw shots it can mean reacting 12%
罚球命中率9%，反应速度提高12%。
faster and so until you experience that
所以，在你亲身体验之前，
it sometimes is hard to grasp how much
很难理解睡眠
of a difference this can make in your
对
life but it is one of the foundations
生活的影响有多大。睡眠是影响你方方面面的基础之一，它包括你的
you function your mood how you feel and
情绪、感受，以及
ultimately perform the following day if
最终影响你第二天的表现。如果
I could offer you or yes you
我能给
specifically see if I could offer you
你提供一些
something that's free and healthy and
免费、健康、
safe that's going to help you think more
安全的东西，帮助你更
clearly make better decisions be in a
清晰地思考、做出更好的决定、拥有
better mood be more productive and
更好的心情、提高工作
efficient would you want it of course
效率，你会想要吗？当然，具体价格是
how much exactly and so it's really a
多少？所以，这其实
decision of whether you want to invest
取决于你是否愿意投入
uh your time to be able to be more
时间，更加
proactive with this particular area of
积极主动地改善睡眠，
your life to get the benefits that come
从而获得它带来的益处。
down the road with it who do you work
你和哪些人合作过？请你大致介绍一下
you've worked with on sleep and why have
你在睡眠方面合作过的个人和机构，以及他们为什么选择和
they come to you I've had an opportunity
你合作。 多年来，我有机会
to work with a number of professional
与许多职业
sports teams and athletes as well as
运动队、运动员以及相关
organizations over the years to try and
组织合作，尝试将
apply the science into practice to help
科学应用于实践，帮助
them improve their sleep their
他们改善睡眠、
scheduling and their travel so for
日程安排和出行。
example I've been with the San Francisco
例如，我曾与美国职业
Giants in Major League Baseball I've
棒球大联盟的旧金山巨人队合作，也曾
worked with um NBA teams like the Golden
与NBA球队（如金
State Warriors uh NFL teams like the
州勇士队）和NFL球队（如
Philadelphia Eagles I won a Super Bowl
费城老鹰队）合作，并于
ring in 2017 with them to um other
2017年随老鹰队赢得了超级碗冠军。此外，我还与
sports organizations like Nike and under
耐克、
arour and ESPN to try and show how you
安德玛和ESPN等其他体育组织合作，尝试展示如何
strictly based on the schedule and
根据赛程安排和
insufficient sleep opportunities um to
睡眠不足来预测NBA球队的失利。我也曾帮助
individual athletes who recognize you
运动员意识到自己在这
know hey this is an area that I am not
方面做得不够好，
optimizing and I know this can be such a
并意识到睡眠不足
valuable asset to extend my career to
对于延长职业生涯、
prevent injuries down the road and to
预防伤病以及保持
help me be at my best do you ever work
最佳状态至关重要。您是否
with CEOs I do I do work with Executives
与CEO合作过？是的，我与高管合作，
help them be their best because they too
帮助他们发挥最佳水平，因为他们也是
are high performers right their
高绩效人士，只是他们的
performance outcomes are maybe a little
绩效目标可能
bit different than pro athletes where
与职业运动员略有不同。
we're quantifying on field performance
我们正在量化他们在赛场上的表现，
and looking at their swim times and what
观察他们的游泳时间以及
they're doing when it comes to the you
他们在
know onc court or on field um
球场或赛场上的
performance outcomes but for these
表现结果。但对于这些
Executives they arguably are also making
高管来说，他们也必须做出
incredibly important decisions they have
极其重要的决定，他们
to still react when they're under
仍然需要在
pressure and they have to make good
压力下做出反应，做出正确的
judgment calls and so many of the things
判断。
that I coach and and try to recommend to
我指导和推荐给
my lead athletes are very much
我的首席运动员的许多方法，也同样
applicable to the SE Suite executive or
适用于SE Suite的高管，
even just the working professional
甚至适用于任何职场人士。这正是
that's really what what I found so
我觉得
fascinating about your research and your
你的研究和
work is that although there's a focus on
工作最吸引人的地方：虽然你的研究重点是
athletes as someone who is also
运动员，但作为一个经常
traveling is also very very busy also um
出差、非常忙碌的人，我有时也会
struggles with sleep sometimes because
因为需要在
I'm I have to perform late at night
深夜工作（无论是在
whether that's on stage or with meetings
舞台上、开会还是
or whatever it might be I resonated with
其他什么）而难以入睡，我对你的很多观点都深有同感。而且，
gym pretty much every day if I can um
如果可以的话，我几乎每天都会在健身房训练。
and I've also noticed a correlation
我还注意到，我的睡眠质量与
between things like injury in the gym
健身房的伤病情况之间存在关联。
unquote sleep de but I but I I want to
但是，我想
confront two things the first thing I
谈谈两件事，第一件事是…… 我
want to confront is the misconceptions
想探讨的是人们反复
around sleep that you encounter over and
遇到的关于睡眠的误解。有哪些普遍存在的
overarching misconceptions that stand in
误解阻碍了
the way of people believing in and
人们相信并
implementing the advice that you give
实践我给出的建议？
them I'll start with just this badge of
首先，我想谈谈社会上
honor that I really believe still
仍然存在的一种“荣誉勋章”：人们
persists in society where you should get
只需
only four or five hours of sleep and
睡四五个小时就能
should be able to perform at your best
发挥最佳状态。
and I think the tides are turning and I
我认为这种观念正在转变，过去
last several years where there are more
几年里，这种情况发生了变化。
athletes like the Tom Brady who you know
像汤姆·布雷迪这样的精英运动员开始公开倡导提高睡眠质量，他认为
say everything is around performance
一切都是为了提升运动表现，
enhancement I going need to go to to bed
需要早睡早起，才能为新的
be ready to go for the day to you know
一天做好准备。而
the Simone bios who says I need to get 8
西蒙·比奥斯则认为需要
hours of sleep and so I think that that
睡足八小时。因此，我认为这种“
is a badge of honor that is now shifting
荣誉勋章”正在发生转变，人们现在普遍认为，
and now it's going to become well if
如果
sleep right then you're actually at a
睡眠不足八到十小时，实际上会对
decrement to yourself and you're
自身状态产生负面影响，而且会影响你的表现。
whether you're on the field as a pro
无论你是职业
athlete or whether you're leading an
运动员在赛场上拼搏，还是领导一个
organization or trying to go after
组织，或者在追求
whatever ever it is that matters to you
任何对你来说重要的事情，都要让自己做到最好。
right and and I think that's going to
我认为这种观念会不断
continue to shift but I'm excited about
变化，但我对此感到兴奋，
it because that's one thing until you
因为只有
experience that that difference and that
亲身体验过睡眠充足带来的改变和
life transformation of what it feels
生活转变，才能真正体会到它的好处。睡眠
insufficient sleep are there any
不足会让你彻底改变生活，再也不想回到过去那种状态。关于
sleep hygiene and um I know the
睡眠卫生和如何正确睡眠，是否存在一些误解？我知道
quantities of sleep weeny that also seem
睡眠时长似乎也是
to stand in people's way
人们
of them getting a great night's sleep
获得优质睡眠的一大障碍。
yeah so I think that there is a
我认为存在一个
misconception that everyone needs a
误解，认为每个人都需要
certain amount of sleep there's
一定量的睡眠，但实际上睡眠需求
individual variability so the the
因人而异。
recommendation from the American Academy
美国
of sleep medicine and the Sleep research
睡眠医学会和睡眠研究
Society so two of our national
协会——我们美国的两个国家级
organizations here in the US recommend
组织——建议
minimally 7 hours of sleep but that's
至少睡7个小时，但这只是
the lower threshold you might actually
最低标准，你可能
need 8 hours or 9 hours or more to feel
需要8个小时、9个小时甚至更长时间才能感到
well rested right I I personally feel
精神饱满。 我个人觉得睡
terrible on seven hours and I much more
七个小时就感觉很糟糕，我更
need the eight to nine hours and there's
需要八到九个小时。当然，
those in that individual differences so
每个人的情况都不一样，所以
you need to find what you feel well
你需要找到让你感觉
rested you're able to function well at a
休息充分、白天能够高效运转的睡眠时间。这就是
then be your individual requirement so I
你个人的睡眠需求。我
think there's this misperception that
觉得很多人误以为
everyone needs a certain amount but you
每个人都需要固定的睡眠时间，但其实你
need to find what works for you and it's
需要找到适合自己的方法，而这需要循序渐进地做出
all about small changes so if you're not
一些改变。如果你睡不到
at 7 hours I think you shared sometimes
七个小时，我想你也说过有时候
you're you're you're under that oh yeah
你睡得不够，哦，是的，
sometimes yeah you know it's about F 15
有时候，你知道，多睡15
or 30 minutes more can make a difference
到30分钟就能带来很大的不同。
refence so if you're getting 6 hours
所以，如果你现在每天睡六个小时，
then I'm going to recommend getting 15
我建议你这周每天多睡15
minutes or 30 minutes more every day for
到30分钟，
minutes more next week so that you're
下周再多睡15到30分钟，这样你就能
building from say 6 hours of sleep to 6
逐渐从六个小时增加到六个
and a half hours and you may not think
半小时。你可能觉得
that that's that much but we can all do
这不算多，但我们都能做到
15 minutes more right we're less
多睡15分钟，对吧？我们可以少
scrolling or doing what we're wrapping
刷手机或者做其他事情。 我们
up our day but those 15 minutes add up
今天的工作即将结束，但这15分钟的睡眠时间累积起来意义重大。比如，多睡15分钟就能让
where that's a difference of like an a
一个A等
student to a b student or 11 minutes
生升到B等生，或者
more sleep is the difference of a b
多睡11分钟就能让一个B等
student to a c student in one of these
生升到C等生。一项
studies really exactly and then over the
研究表明，睡眠时间的增加确实能起到这样的作用。而且，
course of a week 15 minutes will be
一周下来，多睡15分钟就能比
didn't what was the study so this was a
不睡多睡近2个小时。这项
study done um in high school students
研究是针对高中生进行的，研究内容是睡眠时间
much they're sleeping versus their
与
correlation to to grades and so that
成绩之间的相关性。结果
15minute difference was shown to be that
显示，多睡15分钟就能让
A to B student 11 minutes from that B to
A等生升到B等生，多睡11分钟就能让B等
C student oh gosh yes so it doesn't have
生升到C等生。所以，睡眠时间的增加并不一定意味着成绩的
to be these big jumps
大幅提升，
but small changes over time will will
日积月累的小改变也能产生显著的效果。
add up the the study I have in front of
我手边这份
me here which I've printed out um also
打印出来的研究也
highlights the importance of sleep for
强调了睡眠对
everybody but also specifically in this
每个人的重要性，尤其是
case for athletes can you walk me
对运动员而言。你能给我详细介绍一下
through this study and what you found in
这项研究吗？你在
this particular study on the adult male
针对成年男性
basketball players yes and how you
篮球运动员的研究中发现了什么？
conducted the study so in the study we
这项研究是如何进行的？在研究中，我们
looked at the men's basketball team and
观察了男子篮球队。
we really tried to examine if we
我们尝试研究，如果将
extended their sleep over 5 to 7 weeks
他们的睡眠时间延长5到7周，
encouraging them to get 9 or 10 hours of
鼓励他们每晚睡9到10个小时，以
sleep every single night to B pay back
偿还
what we call an accumulated sleep debt
我们所说的“睡眠债”，
would we see any impact on performance
是否会对他们的运动
outcome specifically would we see an
表现产生
impact on reaction time their fatigue
影响，特别是反应时间、疲劳
levels and would we see an impact on
程度以及
their onc Court performance specifically
场上表现，例如罚球、
free throw shots three-point shots
三分球和
Sprint time and these are measures that
冲刺时间。这些指标
we would do after every regular practice
我们会在每次常规训练后进行测量。在
and over the course of those 5 to 7
5到7
weeks we demonstrated that we saw a 9%
周的时间里，我们发现他们的罚球和三分球命中率分别提高了9%，
a 12% faster reaction time and a 4%
反应时间提高了12%，
increase in uh faster Sprint time and so
冲刺时间提高了4%。
these were the quantification which was
这些量化结果
novel at the time was what was quite
在当时是全新的，也令人非常
fascinating because it wasn't that 1%
着迷，因为这并非像
that I think many Elite athletes are
许多精英运动员那样，为了那1%的提升而绞尽脑汁地
trying to find every small way to adjust
调整
their training to get that 1% better
训练，
better because in Elite Sport that 1%
因为在精英体育中，那1%的提升
can be the difference right of being at
可能决定着他们能否站在
the top versus not but this was arguably
巅峰，而这次的提升幅度却达到了
9% or even double digits for Reaction
9%。 甚至反应时间的提升幅度可以达到两位数，
Time depending on the outcome and so
具体取决于结果。因此，
we've expanded that looking at other
我们将研究范围扩大到其他
sports as well but this was one of the
运动项目，但这项研究是
first ones to show that it really
最早表明它确实有可能对
impact on performance outcome for these
这些运动员的表现产生显著影响的研究之一。
per night to get those results yeah so
为了取得这些成果，他们每晚多睡了多久？是的，他们的确多睡了。
they did so we did quantify objectively
我们
through a uh what's called actigraphy it
通过一种叫做活动记录仪的设备（
looks like a wearable nowadays um and
现在看起来像是一种可穿戴设备）客观地量化了他们的睡眠时间，并将其
then compar that also with what they
与他们
thought they were getting and so we did
认为自己实际的睡眠时间进行了比较。我们确实
extend their sleep um uh substantially
大幅延长了他们的睡眠时间，
over I believe an hour and a half uh
我认为比
to the study because getting 9% more
研究前延长了一个半小时以上。因为坦白说，对于一些球队来说，
free throws or three-point shots or 12%
罚球或三分球命中率提高9%，或者
better reaction time is quite frankly
反应时间提高12%，就可能决定他们能否
like winning a championship and not yeah
赢得冠军。
because I think about the Premier League
因为我经常想到英超联赛，或者说
often which is it's soccer I guess
足球联赛，在
years in my lifetime where both teams
我有生之年，经常会出现两支球队积分
have um tied with the same amount of
相同，最终分差
points and one is one just on the amount
仅为1分的情况。
of goals they've scored they've just
他们的进球数相同，只是多
scored a couple more goals so after 38
进了几个球而已。38场
games they both have the exact same
比赛过后，两人
points and the winner is just the person
积分完全相同，最终的赢家只是多进了
that scored like a couple more goals but
几个球而已。但
even you think of reaction times you
即便你想到反应时间，
think of goalkeepers in in soccer their
想想足球守门员，他们的
whole game is reaction time so if you
整个比赛都依赖于反应时间。所以，如果你
can increase your reaction time by 12%
的反应时间能提高12%，
it's really really staggering
那真的非常惊人，足以
it can be a game changer and I think
改变比赛的走向。我认为，
that's what has been so fascinating with
这正是我合作过的
some of the athletes or organizations
那些运动员、组织
and teams I've worked with who have made
和球队如此引人入胜的原因，他们最终都打进了
it to the most important games and those
最重要的比赛和总
championships because the hope is that
决赛。因为人们希望
you've invested not just the night
你投入的不仅仅是总
before that championship game but you've
决赛前夜，而是
invested an entire season even starting
整个赛季，甚至
in the off season on cultivating better
从休赛期就开始培养更好的
habits to give yourself that foundation
习惯，为自己打下坚实的基础，
and be able to leverage these strategies
并能够运用
that the other team is not because we
对手没有的策略。我们
know that it significantly can impact
知道，这
not just the individual level on
不仅会对个人的表现产生重大影响，也会对整个
performance outcome but organizations as
组织产生重大影响。
a whole and I think one example of that
我认为一个例子
is um I partnered with ESPN to do what
就是，我曾与ESPN合作开展了一个
was called the NBA schedule alert
名为“NBA赛程预警
project where they ask can you predict
项目”的项目，他们会问：你能预测一下
Dr ma when NBA teams are going to be at
马博士什么时候上场吗？  NBA球队
risk of losing games strictly based on
输球的风险完全取决于
the schedule so not factoring in
赛程安排，也就是说，我们忽略了
strength of team but based simply on
球队实力，仅仅根据
their schedule where they're traveling
他们的赛程——包括客场行程、往返次数等因素——来判断球队输球的可能性。
their game outcomes as you mentioned and
正如你提到的，这些因素会影响整个球队和比赛结果。在过去的
over three seasons I was 76 to 86%
三个赛季中，我仅根据赛程就
correct on accurately predicting when an
预测
NBA team will be at highest risk of
NBA球队何时面临最大
losing strictly based on the schedule so
输球风险，准确率达到了76%到86%。所以，为了
in the spirit of the project we didn't
这个项目的初衷，我们没有
factor in strength of team but to me
考虑球队实力，但这个结果让我非常
that was staggering because there's many
震惊，因为还有许多
other factors that maybe are not always
其他因素，虽然它们的
considered to be as clearly important
重要性可能不如
about you know this travel schedule up
赛程安排那么显而易见，
front but hey maybe these factors really
但这些因素确实会以
in this way and that's not the only
这种方式影响比赛结果。这并非唯一
thing that has obviously shown that
表明
organizations and teams as a as a whole
球队和俱乐部整体表现
will have differences performance
会因赛程安排而有所不同的研究。
outcome there's other studies like the
其他研究，例如“
Monday Night Football study that showed
周一夜赛”的研究，表明
if you simply bet on a West Coast team
如果你在25个赛季的夜间比赛中押注西海岸球队对阵东海岸球队，
seasons you'd beat the Las Vegas point
你的收益将超过拉斯维加斯的让分
spread 68% of the time and so if you're
盘口。  68% 的情况下，如果你
able to predict with with greater
能更
accuracy then obviously there is
准确地预测，那么显然，
potentially some gambling outcomes that
一些赌博结果可能
could work in your favor here but really
会对你有利。但真正
being able to show that you would be
能证明你能比
two teams over is that because the West
两队之间的让分盘口预测得更准，关键在于，
sorry the West Coast team has gone which
西海岸球队（抱歉，是西​​海岸球队）已经出发，无论
who's who's traveled it doesn't matter
谁去客场，这都无关紧要。重要的是，
it simply matters that the West Coast
西海岸
team is playing the east Coast team
球队和东海岸球队是
during night games so this can happen on
在夜间比赛。这种情况可能发生在
the west coast it can happen on the East
西海岸，也可能发生在东
Coast the reason why is because
海岸。原因在于，
afternoon to evening around 4: to 8:00
下午晚些时候到晚上 4 点到 8 点左右，球员的表现会更好。
in both scenarios the body clock of the
在两种情况下，
West Coast team because they typically
西海岸球队的生物钟都会受到影响，因为他们通常在
go out just the day before the game it
比赛前一天才出发，所以
feels like they're on the west coast
感觉就像他们还在西海岸一样。
okay right so when you're a West Coast
所以，如果你是西海岸
team and you stay there and the East
球队，你待在那里，而东
Coast team comes out the East Coast is
海岸球队出发，东海岸的时间比你晚
three hours later so what is a seven
三个小时。因此，
o'clock game on a West Coast feels like
西海岸晚上 7 点的比赛感觉就像
a 10 o'clock game for a East Coast team
东海岸球队晚上 10 点的比赛。
got you same thing applies when the West
同样的道理也适用于
Coast team goes east coast even if it's
西海岸球队。 即使是东海岸晚上
a 7:00 game there yeah the West Coast
7 点的比赛，西海岸的
feels like it's a 4:00 body clock yes
生物钟感觉就像是下午 4 点一样，
and so that special window of around 4:
所以下午 4 点
to 8:00 p.m. when world records are
到 8 点这段时间很特别。 当世界纪录被
broken and performance in a 24-hour day
打破，24小时内的表现达到
is is optimal and that is leveraged then
最佳状态，并且这种状态能够持续
over those 25 Seasons that the West
25个赛季，那么
Coast will have more favorable outcome
西海岸的整体成绩将会更有利。我明白了。
overall got you so in this study you did
在你2011年进行的这项研究中，
of the things I read as well is that
我读到的一点是，
players who had slept more in your study
睡眠时间更长的球员
sprinted
冲刺速度
faster I mean quite quite dramatically
更快，而且速度
faster as well I I think from 16.2
提升非常显著。我记得
seconds at the start of the study versus
研究开始时是16.2秒，
15.5 seconds at the end yes over what
结束时是15.5秒。是的，测试
distance was that yes so that was from
距离是多少？是从
the Baseline to half court to Baseline
底线到半场，再到底线
to full court and back so we chose a
到全场，然后再返回。我们选择了一种
very standardized
非常标准化的
sprinting uh sprinting drill that they
冲刺训练，球员们都很
are familiar with that we could
熟悉，我们可以
replicate after every regular practice
在每次常规训练后进行。
as you imagine not everyone on the team
正如你所想，并非球队中的每个人都
was participating on in this study and
参与了这项研究，
so they did this after every regular
所以他们在每次常规训练后都进行这项训练。
practice and that ended up being a 4%
最终，
difference in Sprint time that is pretty
冲刺时间相差了4%，这真是太
crazy do do do professional teams know
不可思议了。职业球队知道吗？
this do athletes know this are they
运动员知道吗？他们
aware of this or is this something
了解吗？还是说这是个
that's fairly new some are aware and I
比较新的发现？ 有些人已经意识到这一点，而且我
think the momentum is shifting towards
认为这种势头正在转变，越来越多的
more athletes more teams recognizing
运动员和球队开始认识到
that this is an untapped competitive
这是一个尚未开发的竞争
advantage that this is an area that they
优势。他们
may or may not have implemented specific
可能已经针对这一领域制定了具体的
strategies or education or or planning
策略、培训或
for when they travel but I think the
旅行计划，也可能还没有。但我认为，那些
more Forward Thinking organizations
更具前瞻性的组织、
teams and athletes are starting to pick
球队和运动员已经开始注意到这一点，并
this up and starting to recognize that
开始意识到
they can use this as a weapon right as a
他们可以将其作为一种武器，甚至可以将其作为一种兴奋剂，
because it is safe it's healthy it's
因为它安全、健康、
effective and we know that it will be
有效，而且我们知道，它将是少数
one of the only things that can give you
能够带来这些性能提升的方法之一。
those are the ones that are trying to
这些人正在尝试
Leverage The Science into application
利用科学来
for optimizing yeah their sleep at
优化他们的夜间睡眠。
nighttime have you seen athletes
你见过运动员，特别是那些通过改善睡眠来
individual athletes change and save
改变甚至挽救
their careers when I say change I mean
自己职业生涯的运动员吗？我说的改变是指
change the trajectory of their career or
改变他们职业生涯的轨迹，或者说
save their careers because they focused
挽救他们的职业生涯。
on their sleep and can you give me some
你能举几个
examples of that yes Golden State
例子吗？是的，金州
Warriors Andre Iguodala he's someone who
勇士队的安德烈·伊戈达拉，
I worked closely with he came to the
我曾与他密切合作过。他大约在
Warriors back in around 2014 he was
2014年加入勇士队，当时他
already an Allstar he was 28 at the time
已经是一位…… 这位当时28岁的全明星球员
knew that his career was going to
知道自己的职业生涯
probably be sunsetting at some future
可能终将落幕，
time but wanted to extend it as long as
但他想尽可能延长自己的职业生涯。
possible but he knew he wasn't doing
然而，他意识到自己的
sleep best as possible he was very open
睡眠质量并不理想。他坦诚地
about sharing how he would stay up till
分享了自己的睡眠习惯：经常熬夜到
the we hours in the morning playing
凌晨玩
video games would sleep for a few hours
电子游戏，睡几个小时，然后去
go to practice play for a few hours come
训练，再打几个小时，
home and take a 2 to three hour power
回家后小睡两三个小时。
nap and that was his routine for for 10
这样的作息持续了
years um and he said you know how do I
十年之久。他问我：“我该如何
improve how I approach my sleep I know
改善睡眠呢？”他明白，对于
who wants to play in the league as long
想要在联盟长久征战的运动员来说，睡眠至关重要。
as possible so I had the opportunity to
因此，我有幸
work with him over several months to
与他合作了几个月，
help him recraft how he approached to
帮助他重新调整
sleep including a wind down routine
睡眠方式，包括制定睡前放松的习惯，调整
thought about some of his nutritional
营养摄入，并
choices tried to shorten his naps time
尝试缩短小睡时间，让小睡时间更
them closer to game time to give him the
接近比赛时间，以
Boost and alertness and performance be
提升他的精神状态、警觉性和比赛表现，帮助他更好地
able to manage a racing mind and be able
控制思绪，并以一种非常有效的
to have just a more proactive approach
方式改善
to his sleep in a really neat way The
睡眠。
Following Season the Warriors went to
接下来的赛季，勇士队多年来
the championship for the first time in
首次打进总决赛，并最终
many years they won he came back with
夺冠。 他带着
the finals MVP he subsequently has won
总决赛MVP的头衔回归，随后又随队赢得了
three more championships with them so
三座总冠军奖杯，
four in total and extended his career
总共四座，并将自己的职业生涯延长了
for 10 years when we made these changes
十年。当我们做出这些改变时，我们对他的
performance enhancement so a third party
表现提升进行了量化分析。第三方机构
Quantified as he went from under seven
量化了他的训练时长，从不到七小时增加到
to seven and a half to more than eight
七个半小时，再到超过八小时，他的
threo percentage he had a
三分球
88.9% increase in his free throw shots
命中率翻了一番，罚球命中率提高了88.9%，这
which very interestingly is the exact
非常有趣，与
same 9% that I showed in my man's
我在球员
basketball study that had the same 9%
篮球研究中发现的罚球命中率提升9%的幅度完全相同。
Improvement in free throws he had a 29%
他的
Improvement in his points per minute a
每分钟得分提高了29%，
45% decrease in his fowls and so you
犯规次数减少了45%。你
know these numbers are pretty staggering
知道，
again for someone who's already at the
对于一位已经达到全
highest level as an Allstar and it's not
明星级别最高水平的球员来说，这些数据确实令人震惊。我并不是要
to take anything away from Andre but he
贬低安德烈，但他
has been very vocal about the difference
一直公开谈论这些改变带来的变化，
he says it changed everything for him
他说这些改变彻底改变了他。
and I think that that's you know a very
我认为这是一个非常
inspiring story of what it can mean to
鼓舞人心的故事，它展现了
extend your career and be able to almost
延长职业生涯的意义所在。 他几乎
tap into this additional performance
挖掘出了自己都意想不到的额外
capacity that I think even he was
潜能，我想连他自己都感到
surprised about that he for the first
惊讶。他第
time was able to improve beyond what he
一次超越了自己
already thought was his best and I think
认为的最佳状态，我认为
that's what's so inspiring because this
这才是最鼓舞人心的地方，因为我们
is something that's accessible to all of
每个人都可以
us to be able to tap into that little
挖掘出自己的潜能。
bit more so not only did he win the most
他不仅赢得了最
valuable player award but his
有价值球员奖，而且他的
three-point conversion went up
三分球命中率提高了
218% yes so during the time that I had
218%。是的，在我与
worked with him his three-o percentage
他合作的那段时间里，他的三分球命中率
went up twofold during that time it begs
翻了一番。这不禁让人
the question what did you do to
好奇，你对他做了什么？
him and you know you named a couple of
你刚才提到了一些，
things there but I'd love to dig into
但我很想深入探讨
some of those key points sure um where
其中的一些关键点。当然，
you started with him the specific sort
你最初是如何帮助他的？
of implement things that you implemented
你具体实施了哪些措施来改善
into his um sleep hygiene and so that if
他的睡眠习惯？如果
I am him the day that you met him when
我是他，在你第一次见到他的时候，他还在
he was taking those naps and staying up
午睡，熬夜（说实话，
late which I often do to be fair um
我经常这样），
where would you start with me and where
你会从哪里开始指导我？
did you start with him okay so let's
你又是如何帮助他的？好的，让我们
dive into is just some very practical
深入探讨一下。我开始用一些非常实用的
strategies that I started to challenge
策略来挑战
him with which was we'll start with his
他，首先……
sleep environment we want to make your
我们希望你的
sleep environment like a cave really
睡眠环境像一个洞穴，真正
dark quiet cool and
黑暗、安静、凉爽、
comfortable dark cave so dark blackout
舒适。遮光
curtains eye mask are some of the
窗帘和眼罩是
easiest tools that you can grab but are
最容易获得的工具，但却
incredibly helpful and great investment
非常实用，也是一项值得的投资，无论
to be able to use that both at home and
在家还是
then when you travel so that if you're
旅行都能使用。例如，如果你身处
in a non-ideal environment like a hotel
不太理想的环境，比如酒店
room you have for example an IM mask
房间，你可以使用眼罩来
that can help dampen out the the light
降低光线，
uh making it quiet so
营造安静的氛围。
earplugs uh also a white noise machine
耳塞也是不错的选择。此外，
I'm a huge fan of even a small travel
我还非常喜欢白噪音机，即使是小型旅行
white noise so that you can actually
白噪音机也行，它可以帮助你
mask over external noises that you may
掩盖那些你无法控制的外部噪音。我习惯在
that tells myself that I sleep with
睡前听点什么，因为
radio in my room so when I'm as an adult
我从小房间里就有收音机，所以
now I'm always looking to play something
现在长大了，我总是会在
as I fall asleep is that going to hurt
入睡前听点什么。这会影响
my Sleep Quality I would say if you're
我的睡眠质量吗？如果你已经习惯了，我认为
to continue to do so I am not a fan of
继续这样做没问题。但我个人不喜欢
light exposed um to you in that hour
在睡前一小时开着电视，让明亮的光线照射到身上。
before bedtime because it also can just
因为它也能
be very psychologically stimulating but
带来很强的心理刺激，但
if like you said it's a radio or it's a
就像你说的，如果
podcast that you feel is helping you
你觉得某个广播或播客能帮助你
relax then I'm a fan of it do you think
放松，那我很喜欢。你觉得
Daria will help people relax it
达莉娅的播客能帮助人们放松吗？
might it might help you at least think
也许吧，它至少能让你
about your sleep a bit more and
更关注自己的睡眠，并
challenge you to do maybe one one change
鼓励你今晚做出一些改变。
tonight we consider that to be a
我们认为这可以算作对这个
scientific endorsement of of the podcast
播客的科学认可。
um okay so I've got sound down you are a
嗯，好的，声音没问题。你
fan of the white white noise machines I
喜欢白噪音机吗？
am because sometimes there's external
是的，因为有时候会有一些外部
noises like a garbage truck or
噪音，比如垃圾车或
construction that you're not always able
建筑工地的噪音，你无法
to control so if you can at least mask
控制。所以，如果你能暂时掩盖这些噪音，
over it temporarily that can sometimes
有时可以
be helpful to keep individuals more
帮助人们
asleep during the night time and there's
在夜间睡得更好。
even some now that are adaptive so if
现在甚至有一些是自适应的，比如如果
the door slams then the volume
门被关上，音量会
temporarily increases and then will
暂时增大，然后
decrease so there's almost these smart
减小。所以市面上出现了一些智能
white noise machine that are that are
白噪音机。以上是
coming out on the market so that's from
从
a noise standpoint and earplugs are
噪音角度来说的。耳塞在
going to be helpful if you're traveling
旅行时会很有帮助，在家时，
when you're at home you can obviously
你当然可以
use those to dampen down any external
用它们来降低任何外部噪音。
noise from a from a temperature
从温度的
standpoint you want it to be cool I
角度来看，你肯定希望房间凉爽。我
think this is an area that a lot of
认为很多
people can benefit from because they
人都能从中受益，因为他们
often sleep in much warmer temperatures
通常睡在
than what we know is probably more
比我们所知的更
conducive to sleep which is cooler 60 to
适宜睡眠的温度高得多的环境中。研究表明，凉爽的60到
67° has been shown to help individuals
67华氏度（约16到19摄氏度）有助于人们
stay asleep and fall asleep that may be
保持睡眠并更快入睡。这个温度
frigidly cold for some but you have to
对某些人来说可能太冷了，但你必须
find the temperature that's right for
找到适合
you I would say decrease your
自己的温度。我的建议是，
degrees every couple of days and then
每隔几天将温度降低一到两度，这样
you can find the temperature that works
你就能找到最适合自己的温度。
now where there's mattress covers that
现在甚至还有床垫罩
can help you regulate temperature from
可以帮助你调节温度，从
much cooler to warmer so if there's
凉爽到温暖。如果你的
differences in bed Partners that's a way
伴侣对温度的偏好不同，这可以让
that you can actually accommodate both
你同时满足
of their preferences so that's about 16
双方的需求。这个温度大约是16
to 20° cus
到20华氏度（约-7到-7摄氏度）。但是，如果
what about when I shower or I bath
我洗澡或泡澡后直接上床睡觉呢？
because often I go and have a shower
因为我经常洗澡后就
then I get straight into bed after yes
直接上床睡觉。这样做好
is that good or bad I would encourage
还是不好？我建议
you to shift that timing a little bit
你把洗澡或泡澡的时间
earlier into the night so an hour and a
提前一点，比如在
half before you are planning to go to
你计划
bed I would shift your shower because
睡觉前一个半小时。 我会建议你调整一下淋浴时间，因为
when you are taking a hot bath or hot
热水澡或热水
shower it increases your core
淋浴会升高你的核心
temperature but when you fall asleep
体温，但入睡后
your core temperature drops so you don't
核心体温会下降，所以你不
want that competing signal to be right
希望在睡前出现这种相互干扰的信号。
before bedtime but if you back that
如果你把
shower up an hour and a half that should
淋浴时间推迟一个半小时，应该就
be sufficient time that we think
足够了，我们认为这
potentially there's an augmentation of
可能
helping that drop in temperature and
有助于降低体温。
some smaller Studies have shown that
一些小型研究表明，
that can help decrease the time to fall
这有助于缩短
asleep and also enhance deep sleep which
入睡时间，并增强深度睡眠，这
has implications for Muscle Recovery
对肌肉恢复
regeneration and you get more of that in
和再生至关重要。你在晚上早些时候能获得更多的肌肉恢复和再生。
the earlier part of your night so it's
所以，这是
an easy fix uh just to tweak the timing
一个简单的解决方法，只需调整一下热水澡或
of your shower in your hot bath to be
热水浴的时间，在睡前
just an hour or two before bedtime not
一两个小时进行，而不是在
right before bed so it's a strategy too
睡前。
if you have difficulties winding down
如果你难以放松身心，这也是一个策略，可以在
shower hot bath earlier in the evening
晚上早些时候进行热水澡或热水浴。
one of the problems I also have when I
我有时也会遇到
sleep sometimes is I I hear people say
睡眠问题，我听说有人说
hours before bed however I sometimes you
睡前3到4个小时不能吃东西，但我有时晚上
know I sometimes get home at 10:00 p.m.
10点才到家。   晚上
and I get home hungry as hell at 10 p.m.
10点到家时，我饿得要命。
and then sometimes if I order food for
有时候，比如我点外卖，
for example it might come at like 11:00
可能要到11点才能送到，这
okay which means I end up eating at
意味着我最后也是
11:00 and then I really see it in my
11点才吃东西。然后我发现这会影响我的
sleep schools
睡眠，
um I think as well that I'm someone that
我觉得自己更容易
tends to fall asleep later again this
晚睡。这
might just be me telling BS to myself
可能只是我自己的胡思乱想，
but that's what tends to happen and I
但事实就是如此。我
know I'm not supposed to eat before bed
知道睡前不应该吃东西，
but I'm so hungry so is there anything
但我真的好饿。所以，有没有什么东西
that I can eat before bed that won't
可以在睡前吃，既不会
disrupt my sleep but will get rid of The
影响睡眠，又能消除
Hunger yes the preference is not to have
饥饿感呢？当然，最好不要
a huge meal right before bed that's
在睡前吃太多
fried fatty um you know really heavy
油腻的食物，你知道，那种很重的食物会一直留
sitting in your stomach that hour right
在胃里，尤其是在
before bedtime um so if you're able to
睡前一个小时。所以，如果你能把握好
time that and be strategic then that's
时间，合理安排，那当然是最好的。
obviously the preference but I'm okay
但我也可以接受
with you having a pre-sleep snack a lot
你在睡前吃点零食。
of times for my athletes that means
很多时候，对于我的运动员来说，
we'll go for something like 50% of a
我们会选择50%的
complex carb and like 50% of a lean
复合碳水化合物和50%的瘦肉
protein so for example cereal and milk
蛋白。比如，麦片加牛奶
is an easy one cereal yes cereal and
就是一个简单的选择。麦片，没错，就是麦片。
milk of course we want something that's
当然，我们想要的是
whole grain uh and not you know
全谷物食品，嗯，
necessarily A sugary you know cereal but
不一定是含糖的麦片，比如牛奶。牛奶
Cal and milk is an easy one that's many
加钙片是个不错的选择，很多
people have access to or cottage cheese
人都能买到。或者也可以是干酪
and fruit or 100% ho whe crackers and
加水果，或者100%全麦饼干加
peanut butter and the reason why is
花生酱。之所以推荐牛奶，是
because I don't want you waking up in
因为我不想让你
the middle of the night being hungry or
半夜饿醒，或者
even trying to fall asleep and you feel
想睡着的时候感觉
like you're hungry but we want something
饿。我们想要的是能
that's slow digesting through the night
在夜间缓慢消化的食物，
because ideally you're going to be
因为理想情况下，你
sleeping S 8 n hours during the night uh
晚上应该睡8个小时，
and we want it to be able to get you to
我们希望它能让你撑到
the morning time and then you will fuel
早上，醒来后就能补充能量。
when you wake up so a pre-sleep snack
所以，如果你
coming home late and you want to
回家很晚，想在睡前
obviously be able to fuel before bed or
补充能量，或者
if you have a really early dinner and
如果你晚餐吃得很早，睡前感到
you're hungry before bedtime yeah that
饿，睡前吃点东西是个好办法。这种情况也
happens sometimes as well sometimes I'll
经常发生，有时候我会在下午
eat dinner at about 5:00 p.m. Y and then
5点左右吃晚饭。  Y，然后
I get to about 10 11:00 p.m. I'm still
我就到了晚上10点到11点左右。 我还没睡，
awake and I'm starving okay so what's a
饿得不行，所以，
pre-sleep snack that you think you can
你觉得睡前吃点什么比较好？
grab for some nuts okay yeah does that
坚果怎么样？可以，坚果
work yeah yeah nuts have protein in them
里有蛋白质，
um yeah you can grab a good nut mix
嗯，你可以吃点混合坚果，
maybe you can partner that also with
也许还可以搭配
like some yogurt too raspberries
一些酸奶、覆盆子，对，
raspberries yeah fruit yeah and some
水果，还有
yeah a a protein and carbon there and
蛋白质和碳水化合物，
those are good good pre-sleep snack
这些都是不错的睡前零食。
what's the if I wanted to destroy my
如果我想彻底毁掉
sleep what would you recommend I eat
睡眠，你建议我睡前吃什么？
right before bed what would you
睡前吃什么？
bed it can be if you just want to
如果你只想
destroy your entirely okay so we're
彻底毁掉睡眠，那就吃点吧。
bed okay so some alcohol yeah we'll have
好吧，那我们睡前喝几杯，来点“睡前小酌”。酒精，我们会喝点
some alcohol on board we'll we'll throw
酒，还会加点
in some caffeine too to to really get
咖啡因，让
you to stay awake in the next couple of
你在接下来的几个小时里保持清醒。我们还会吃
hours we add a really heavy meal that's
一顿油腻的食物，比如
Fried Tomato based um fatty sitting in
油炸番茄之类的，嗯，脂肪会留在
your stomach right before bed and you
你的胃里。你
say tomato based yeah sometimes
说番茄？嗯，有些
individuals will have acid reflux with
人吃番茄制品会引起胃酸反流。
tomato based products and so if that's
如果
something that you experience then you
你确实有这种经历，那么你
generally want to avoid some of the
通常应该避免食用一些
Tomato based products that can aggravate
番茄制品，因为它们会加重
some of the acid reflux so some fried
胃酸反流。比如一些油炸
food with some
食品配番茄酱，是的，
ketchup yes okay so alcohol caffeine and
好的，酒精、咖啡因和
some fried food with some ketchup I
一些油炸食品配番茄酱，我
think that would really work to your
认为这会在夜间对你非常
disadvantage during the nighttime any
不利。任何
sugar yes sugary carbs are tends to be
糖分，是的，含糖碳水化合物往往是
particularly also sleep deprived so
睡眠不足时人们的偏好，所以
people will choose more carb heavy foods
人们会选择碳水化合物含量高、
and foods that have um less fiber and
纤维含量低、
more more sugar why fats is it that if I
糖分含量高的食物，脂肪含量低。如果我
eat those Foods before bed it impacts my
在睡前吃这些食物，会影响我的
sleep what what what's going on I don't
睡眠吗？到底是怎么回事？我
think we have a great understanding of
认为我们对此了解得还不够深入。
that I think the field of sleep and
睡眠和
nutrition is definitely growing and I
营养领域正在蓬勃发展，我
think down the road in the next five or
认为在未来五到
10 years we hopefully we'll have more
十年内，我们有望找到更多
answers to that but it's a fast area
答案。这是一个快速发展的领域，
that we do start to understand what we
我们开始了解到，我们的
eat can affect our sleep so for example
饮食会影响我们的睡眠，例如
the stages of our sleep or how we sleep
睡眠阶段或
during the night time some of the
夜间睡眠质量。一些
smaller studies shown what you eat can
小型研究表明，饮食会影响睡眠。 这可能会
then affect having more Awakenings
导致夜间醒来次数增多，
during the nighttime um and affecting
进而影响
the quality of your sleep but I think
睡眠质量。但我认为
many of them are still at the infancy
很多相关研究还处于起步阶段，
because that's certainly something I can
因为我对此深有体会。
months ago I think it was last year
几个月前，大概是去年吧，
actually when I I was staying in a hotel
我住在洛杉矶的一家酒店，
here in LA and I had a cookie before bed
睡前吃了一块饼干。
because it was cuz I'm bloody you know I
你知道，我得
blame the hotel I don't really blame the
怪酒店，其实我并不怪
hotel I take full responsibility it was
酒店，我完全承担责任。饼干
in the mini bar and I hadn't eaten all
在迷你吧里，我一整天都没吃东西，
day I'd came back I'd been working all
回来后一直在工作。当我
been working a lot I'm much more likely
工作了一整天之后，就更容易想吃些
to reach for something bad and I had
不健康的食物。我吃了
this cookie and honestly I woke up the
那块饼干，结果
next morning 8 hours later feeling like
第二天早上醒来，感觉就像
I hadn't slept at all I just felt so
没睡过一样，非常
tired and I know it was that Bloody
疲惫。我知道肯定是那块该死的
cookie cuz I looked at my um my whoop
饼干害的，因为我看了看我的心率，
hashad investor and I could see that my
发现我
heart rate throughout the night was
整晚的心率都
really high like atypically high my
非常高，高得不正常。
heart rate throughout the night will
整晚我的心率
usually just be this nice flat I don't
通常都很平稳，大概
know 50 55 beats per minute and when I'd
每分钟50到55次。但吃了
had that cookie it it started and pretty
那块饼干之后，心率就开始飙升，而且在接下来的
much stayed for the first 3 or 4 hours
三四个小时里几乎一直保持在每分钟
about 75 beats so it was like my body
75次左右。感觉就像我的身体
was was still on it was like I was
还在运转，就像我还在
walking MH um and so I've always just
走路一样。所以我一直觉得，如果
something like that right before bed
在睡前吃类似的东西，
like puts your body under a lot of
会给身体带来很大的
strain like metabolic strain then it's
压力，比如代谢压力，那么
kind of like your body doesn't fall
身体就很难
asleep and my REM sleep's always
入睡。如果我吃了类似的东西，我的快速眼动睡眠也会
attacked as well if I if I if I were to
受到影响。是的，这
very fascinating I think we're starting
非常令人着迷。我认为我们开始逐渐
to understand the connection of what we
了解我们所
eat how our gut is responding to that
吃的食物、我们的肠道如何对此做出反应，
and then how that potentially can affect
以及这些反应如何影响我们的
your sleep and then ultimately your
睡眠，最终影响我们
daytime functioning the next day but we
第二天白天的状态。我们
do recognize from sleep deprivation
从睡眠剥夺
studies uh that individuals will make
研究中发现，人们在晚上会做出
different nutritional choices and grab
不同的营养选择，
night than they would if they were well
比起睡眠充足的时候，他们会更倾向于吃饼干、冰淇淋和其他零食。
rested that's a real horrible Paradox
休息充足？这真是个可怕的悖论，
isn't it it is do you know what I mean
不是吗？你明白我的意思吗？
like if you're tired then you're going
如果你很累，
to eat bad things right before bed which
睡前就会吃些不健康的食物，这
is going to make you sleep worse and
会让你睡得更差，更累，然后
you eat bad things before bed is vicious
你又会睡前吃更多不健康的食物，形成恶性
cycle it is and unfortunately that could
循环。不幸的是，这
potentially lead to potential weight
可能会导致
gain and other Downstream consequences
体重增加和其他一些后续问题。所以，
making sure you're having sufficient
确保充足的
sleep but also having good practices and
睡眠固然重要，但养成良好的睡眠习惯和方法也同样
priority so you're asking what else did
重要。你可能会问，
we do with Andre but in that ways of
我们还为安德烈做了什么？在
preparing to sleep you know we addressed
准备睡眠方面，我们探讨了
does he have a windown routine so we
他是否有固定的睡眠窗口期。我们让
implemented one where he would read
他睡前阅读，以此
before bed to actually relax and prepare
放松
his brain and body to sleep for the
身心，为
night managing a racing mind can be
睡眠做好准备。对于兴奋的运动员来说，以及我们所有人来说，控制思绪纷乱都是
incredibly common for not just the elate
非常普遍的。
athlete but for for all of us and so
所以，在
even before he did that reading we'd
阅读之前，我们会让
actually have him stretch and process
他做一些伸展运动，
his thoughts outside of bed and that set
在床外整理思绪。这为
him up with a two-part system so that he
他建立了一个两步系统，让他
could actually be strategic about
能够更有策略地为
preparing to sleep for the night a lot
睡眠做好准备。很多
of people can relate to this managing a
人都有类似的经历。 对于
racing mind athletes um performers
运动员、表演者和创意人士来说，如何管理思绪纷乱是很常见的。
creatives um so if I've got a racing
如果我
mind I think as well I think I tend to
思绪纷乱，我
feel like I have my best ideas just
感觉自己最好的想法往往是在
before I'm about to get in bed what
临睡前涌现的。
would you recommend someone do if they
如果有人思绪纷乱，你会建议他们怎么做呢？思绪纷乱
have a racing mind again incredibly
非常
common to have racing thoughts thinking
普遍，人们会不停地思考一天的事情，
through the day needing to process your
需要整理
thoughts about how to prepare for
思路来为
tomorrow so what I'd recommend is
明天做准备。所以我建议
every single night so that can mean I
每天晚上花10分钟时间在床外，在昏暗的灯光下整理思绪。这可以是
would recommend you could do stretching
伸展运动，也
H you could do deep breathing exercises
可以是深呼吸练习，
to activate your parasympathetic system
以激活副交感神经系统，
and dampen down your sympathetic system
抑制交感神经系统。
that's what I recommend for a lot of my
我经常这样建议我的
athletes if that's not your thing I
运动员。如果这些方法不适合你，我
recommend journaling getting your
建议你写日记，把你的
thoughts down onto paper uh or writing a
想法记录在纸上，或者列一个
to-do list
待办事项清单。
those are easy ones that all of us can
这些都是我们所有人都能做的简单方法，
do for even if you start with 5 minutes
即使你今天只花5分钟。我现在要去
today so I'm going to stretch um I've
伸展一下。
read I read something I think it was
我读过一些东西，我想是
whoops data they released at the end of
Whoops公司在年底发布的数据，
the year where they because there's an
因为……
activity log in whoop where you
Whoop 里有个活动日志，你
basically say what you're doing and I'm
基本上可以记录你在做什么。我可能
going to butcher this but I think the
记不太清了，但
stats said that reading before bed
统计数据显示，睡前阅读能让
everyone that was using ROP which makes
所有使用 ROP 的用户睡眠质量提高约 5%。这很
sense because you're going to be away
合理，因为睡前阅读可以让你远离
from Light I guess and you're also going
光线，还能
to be calming your you called it your
舒缓你的副
parasympathetic nervous system yes the
交感神经系统。没错，就是副交感神经
parasympathetic nervous system what do I
系统。关于副交感神经系统，
need to know about that in the context
在睡眠方面我需要了解什么呢？它就是
helps you relax and wind down the it is
帮助你放松和平静下来的系统。它
in balance with the sympathetic system
与交感神经系统保持平衡。
which you may have heard is the fight or
你可能听说过交感神经系统，也就是“战斗或
flight system that gets you going that's
逃跑”系统，它会让你进入战斗或逃跑状态，这时
where your heartbe heartbeat will be
你的心跳会
much more rapid your breathing can be
加快，呼吸也会
much more rapid when you need to go
加快。当你需要行动的时候，就是过度思考的时候。
that's when I'm overthinking yes but you
没错，但
want to dampen that down and you want to
你需要抑制这种状态，
activated so you can help actually relax
激活副交感神经系统，这样才能真正帮助
physiologically your body and also your
你的身体和
brain so that you're in a better state
大脑从生理上放松下来，让你更容易
to sleep at night right it's easier to
入睡。这样更容易
slowly pump your brakes and then try to
慢慢地放松下来。 试着
sleep versus if you were going 60 M an
入睡，而不是像在高速公路上以每小时 60 英里的速度行驶，
hour on a freeway and then suddenly
然后突然
slamming on the brakes and just jumping
猛踩刹车，直接跳到
into bed so you actually have a process
床上那样。你需要一个让
to slow yourself down your brain and
自己的大脑和身体慢下来的过程，
body it will help prepare you to
这有助于你
actually get better sleep during the
在夜间获得更好的睡眠。最后，我
night time just want to close off on
想谈谈
Andrew then is there anything else you
安德鲁。你还为
did with him to yes there's please give
他做了些什么吗？是的，请告诉
me there's more that we've done with
我。我们为安德鲁做了很多，
Andre but this is to give you some
但这里只给你一些
highlights so you know approaches to his
重点。关于他的
sleep were having that way to process
睡眠，我们采取了一些方法来处理
his thoughts being able to wind down
他的想法，让他能够
before bed and relax improving his sleep
在睡前放松身心，改善他的睡眠
environment so that it was as I
环境，就像我
mentioned dark and cool I believe his
提到的那样，保持黑暗凉爽。我记得他卧室的温度大约是
was around 67 degrees it was quiet um we
67 华氏度（约 19 摄氏度），而且很安静。我们
tried to we took out technology from his
尝试把电子产品从他的
bedroom so he didn't have that exposure
卧室里拿走，这样他
prior to bed we looked at cutting down
在睡前就不会接触到这些。我们还考虑减少
some of his power naps that were several
他一些长达几个
hours long to shorten them to 20 to 30
小时的午睡，把每次午睡的时间缩短到 20 到 30
minutes and time it much closer to game
分钟，并且安排在比赛
time so we would get that boost as you
时间附近，这样他就能在
would go into evening
晚上
games um and we looked at some of his
比赛前获得能量。我们还关注了他的一些
nutritional choices but this is the
饮食选择，但以上就是
highlight of of some of the ways that we
重点。 我们采取了一些
were strategic about his approach to
策略性措施来改善他的
sleep and while we're also extending his
睡眠，同时我们也延长了他的
sleep from that under 7 to 7 and 1 12 to
睡眠时间，从不足7小时增加到7小时，再到12小时甚至
8 hours because we knew he had an
8小时，因为我们知道他
probably for many months to years prior
之前几个月甚至几年睡眠不足，积累了严重的睡眠债。
to this and so as we've shared some of
正如我们之前分享的，他的一些
the performance outcomes were
表现提升令人
astonishing and he's been very vocal
惊叹，他也一直积极
about sharing his sleep story and he's
分享自己的睡眠故事。他
not the only one um if I could share
并不是唯一一个受益者。嗯，如果可以的话，我想再分享
another story about another athlete
一个关于其他运动员的故事，
where you've asked what has saved
你们问过是什么拯救了
someone's career so with Andre I think
他们的职业生涯。安德烈·巴里摩尔（Andre Barry）的例子是，
he saw this performance enhancement that
他发现了
he could tap into that was that was um
自己可以利用的提升运动表现的方法，而这在
previously he didn't know almost existed
他之前几乎是闻所未闻的。
right but then there's other athletes
但还有其他一些运动员，
where I think having sleep as a
我认为
foundation almost save their career one
充足的睡眠几乎挽救了他们的职业生涯，
example is Ryan Jensen so Ryan Jensen
瑞恩·詹森（Ryan Jensen）就是一个例子。瑞恩·詹森被
was cut from the Ravens and put on the
巴尔的摩乌鸦队裁掉，下放到
practice squad and during this time as
训练队。据说，在那段时间里，
the story goes his father said you know
他的父亲说：“你知道
what's happening you're not yourself you
发生了什么吗？你和平时不一样，你
like made your mom cry the other day you
前几天把你妈妈都弄哭了，你
know there there's something that's
知道，肯定有什么事发生了。”
going on and he eventually was tested
他最终接受了
for sleep apnea which is a very very
睡眠呼吸暂停的检查，这是一种非常
common sleep disorder where your Airway
常见的睡眠障碍，患者在夜间呼吸时气道会发生
has some partial or full collapse during
部分或完全塌陷，导致
very fragmented sleep through the night
睡眠断断续续。
and he was eventually tested diagnosed
他最终确诊后接受了
called a CPAP or continuous positive
CPAP（持续
airway pressure so it's a it's a mask
气道正压通气）治疗。CPAP是一种面罩，通过
that provides air to keep the airway
提供空气来保持气道
open so then you actually can have
畅通，从而帮助患者
Consolidated sleep during the nighttime
在夜间获得完整的睡眠。
and in a very neat way four years later
四年后，瑞恩·詹森以非常巧妙的方式重返赛场，并
Ryan Jensen comes back signs a $42
签下了一份价值4200万美元的
million contract as one of the highest
合同，成为
paid centers in the NFL and then 3 years
NFL收入最高的中锋之一。三年后，也就是
2021 wins the Super Bowl with Tom Brady
2021年，他与汤姆·布雷迪
on the Bucks I see this as the success
所在的雄鹿队一起赢得了超级碗。我认为这是
story of Saving his career and he's been
他职业生涯的“救星”故事。他曾多次
vocal about how much of a difference it
公开表示，CPAP治疗对他职业生涯的巨大影响，让他从
made from literally almost the end of
几乎走到
his career happening to now being able
职业生涯末期，到如今能够
to succeed at the highest level and also
在最高水平的赛场上取得成功，当然，也让他更加
of course being healthier and being able
健康，
to have um more success on the field
在球场上取得了
than he probably imagined for himself
比他自己想象中更大的成就，
and better relationships presumably he's
并且拥有了更好的人际关系。想必他
not made his mother cry I'm quite
的母亲也没有因此而哭泣。 我很
curious about that why is it that when
好奇，为什么
we haven't slept we're more likely to
睡眠不足时我们更容易
make people cry because we are our
让别人哭泣？因为睡眠不足时，我们的
emotions are not regulated well when
情绪调节能力会下降，
we're short on sleep we are more
我们会更容易
irritable we are more grouchy we respond
烦躁、易怒，更容易用情绪化的方式回应。那么，
being able to um why we respond with our
为什么我们会用
emotions yeah what's going on in the
情绪来回应呢？身体里发生了什么？是
brain is it my hormones is it something
大脑的不同区域在起作用吗？是激素水平的问题吗？还是
else it's probably a combination of both
其他什么原因？可能是两者兼而有之。
right we know that um our emotional
我们知道，睡眠充足和睡眠不足时，我们的情绪
regulation is not the same if we're well
调节能力是不同的。
and so we rely more on our innate
因此，我们会更多地依赖于本能反应，而这种反应
response which may not necessarily be
未必是
that which is strategic for what we
我们在睡眠充足、精神饱满的情况下
should be responding with if we were
应该采取的策略。
belt um so we ask cognitively there's a
所以，从认知角度来看，这会影响
brain you're going to be using but then
你使用大脑的哪个部分来应对情绪，但同时，
also you are just not in a state in
你也会处于一种无法像平时那样做出正确反应的状态。是
otherwise is it the amydala that's the
杏仁核在起作用吗？
emotional center that is one that's
情绪中心，也就是
where like fear is very much um and
恐惧和各种
emotions and and um yeah the amydala is
情绪所在的地方，是的，杏仁核，
where like fear and emotions are are
恐惧和情绪
often centered because I've started when
通常都集中在那里。自从
I started learning more about sleep and
我开始更多地了解睡眠以及
the impact it has on my emotions I could
它对情绪的影响后，我
see a huge VAR in how
发现睡眠不足会极大地影响
um how I make my decisions but also how
我的决策方式，以及我的反应速度。
slept yeah and so on the days now where
所以，在那些没睡好的日子里，
I haven't slept I literally have a
我会
conversation with myself and tell myself
和自己对话，告诉自己
that I'm going to be in my M mdala today
今天我的杏仁核会处于活跃状态，尽量
so to try not to make any decisions try
不要做任何决定，也尽量少和
not to talk to many people because
人说话，因为这样
there's a risk that I might just be I
我可能会
might be too short in how I consider
在思考
things and how I respond and I really
问题和做出反应时过于冲动，而我真的
want to stay away from that but I've
想避免这种情况。我
seen such a huge huge variant and I've
发现睡眠不足对我的情绪影响非常大，我
also heard of other like famous CEOs and
也听说过其他一些知名CEO，
stuff like that talk about how they they
他们
focus so much on their sleep I can't was
非常重视睡眠。
reading something the other day and it
前几天我读到一篇文章，好像是
was I think it was it was Jeff Bezos do
杰夫·贝佐斯写的，
you know what I'm gonna say I don't but
你知道吗？ 我个人并不这么认为，但
Jeff Bezos is someone who has been an
杰夫·贝佐斯一直
advocate about sleep and vocal that he
倡导睡眠，他公开表示自己
needs eight hours every night yes the
每晚需要八小时睡眠。是的，
quote that I heard him say or someone
我听他说过，或者有人
told me that he said was I think it
告诉我他说过，好像是
might have been Ariana Huffington
阿里安娜·赫芬顿说的。
actually he said that his job as a CEO
他说，作为CEO，他的工作
is to make decisions and he says he
就是做决策，但他一年
doesn't have to make that many decisions
不需要做很多决策，一年
a year he only makes a couple of big
只需要做几个重大
decisions a year every day he's probably
决策，他每天可能也就
just making two or three big decisions
做两三个。
so if his job is to make decisions then
所以，既然他的工作是做决策，那么
his job is also to sleep because the
睡眠也是他的工作之一，因为
variance I see in even my own decision-
我发现，即使是我自己，睡眠充足
making when I'm slept and underslept is
和睡眠不足时，决策能力的差异也令人难以置信。我每天要
that sits here for seven eight hours a
坐在这里七八个小时，有时还要和别人
conversations you wouldn't believe the
聊天，你绝对想象不到，
difference when my brain and my mouth
当我的大脑和嘴巴
are like connected because I've slept
因为睡眠充足而连接在一起时，我的状态有多么不同，
it's like a different human being it's a
就像换了一个人，换了个
different podcast host um have you got
播客主持人。嗯，你有
data to support this this impact on
数据支持睡眠对
cognitive performance yes so you
认知能力的影响吗？有的，所以，
definitely make better decisions when
当你休息充足时，你肯定能做出更好的决策。
judgment when you're well rested and
睡眠充足时，认知错误的可能性更小，判断力更强，
you're going to react faster so in the
反应速度也更快。因此，在
situations where you need to make big
需要做出重大
decisions whether it's on the field and
决策的情况下，无论是在球场上需要快速
you need to react because you're running
反应接球，还是像
a pass whe whether you are Jeff Bezos
杰夫·贝佐斯那样
and you're running a company and you
经营公​​司
need to make critical decisions um under
需要做出关键决策，尤其是在面临
under sometimes you know acute stressors
急性压力
or you are someone who just is trying to
或努力做到
be your best we know that the cognitive
最好的时候，我们都知道，充足的睡眠对认知
domain very much is influenced by
能力有着显著的影响。一些
I would say you know large um very very
重大
public disasters have happened as a
灾难的发生，正是由于
result of what we know is sleep loss um
睡眠不足，导致
where people have made poor decisions or
人们做出错误的决策，最终酿成
disaster so for example the Challenger
悲剧。例如，挑战者号
disaster with a space shuttle that
航天飞机爆炸事故。事故发生后，相关部门展开了
investigations of why did this happen
调查，
and the final report does suggest that
最终报告指出，
insufficient sleep for some of those key
一些关键决策者睡眠不足，导致
launch or not was attributed to fatigue
疲劳，最终酿成灾难。
and insufficient sleep so being able to
因此，无法在关键
make good Dame time decisions had this
时刻做出正确的决策，
disastrous effect ultimately on the
最终导致了
Challenger explosion or are you aware of
挑战者号的爆炸。 或者您是否了解
any studies that have measured cognitive
任何测量
performance on and sleep yes so my
睡眠与认知表现之间关系的研究？是的，我和
studies as well as many of my other
我的许多
colleagues particularly look at reaction
同事的研究都特别关注反应
time because we know reaction time is um
时间，因为我们知道反应时间
very finely or is very sensitive to
对睡眠不足非常敏感，
sleep loss and I'm starting to find it
而且我开始发现它对
also is sensitive to extension of sleep
睡眠时间的延长也很敏感。
so the other half of the story when you
所以，另一方面，当我们
pay back sleep sleep debt we see that
偿还睡眠债时，我们会看到
benefit on on uh reaction time but uh
反应时间的改善。但是，
reaction time and looking at aspects of
反应时间以及
you know how quickly you're able to
你能够多快做出
respond or if you're having errors when
反应，或者你在不应该做出反应的时候是否出现错误，
those are um tests that are typically
这些都是
used in a lot of sleep studies because
许多睡眠研究中常用的测试，因为
we know is quite sensitive can you give
我们知道它非常敏感。您能给
me an example of a study that will
我举一个研究的例子，让
convince me that um if I sleep more my
我相信如果我睡得更多，我的
cognitive performance will improve one
认知表现就会提高吗？
of the studies I mentioned before even
我之前提到的一项研究，即使只多
15 15 minutes more sleep was that
睡15分钟，也能使A级
difference of that a student to the B
学生和B级
student there's another study I often
学生之间的差异。我经常引用的另一项研究表明，
cite where if you look at the difference
如果你观察
of someone who gets 9 hours of sleep for
一个人连续一周每天睡9个小时，他的
a full week the reaction time stays very
反应时间将保持非常
consistent great you want to react
稳定。 很好，你想做出
appropriately you want to not make
恰当的反应，不想出现
cognitive errors or lapses in judgment
认知错误或判断失误，
and that will be consistent over the
而且这种状态会持续
week if you're someone who's getting
一周。如果你
seven hours of sleep you see a slowing
睡够7个小时，你会发现
of that reaction time and then a
反应时间会变慢，然后趋于
leveling off if you are getting 5 hours
稳定；如果你只睡5个小时，
of sleep you see an even sharper decline
你会发现反应速度下降得更厉害，
in being able to react fast and then you
然后也趋于稳定；
see a leveling off if you're getting
如果你
three hours of sleep every night you're
每晚只睡3个小时，你的
just going to tank that reaction time
反应时间会急剧下降，反应也会
and be slower at the same time you have
变慢，同时判断失误也会
more lapses in judgment and not able to
更多，无法做出
respond appropriately but the the thing
恰当的反应。但
about this study that I find so
这项研究最让我
fascinating is when we know that there's
着迷的地方在于，我们知道，在睡眠
slower in the seven and the 5our group
7小时和5小时的人群中，反应速度都会变慢，但之后会趋于稳定。
there's this leveling off so people say
所以人们会说，
oh can I get used to getting
哦，我可以习惯
insufficiency sleep in some sense there
睡眠不足吗？某种程度上来说，睡眠不足确实会
was this stabilizing of it but the
稳定下来。但
reality is you're not at your best right
事实是，你的状态并非最佳。
we know what your reaction time could be
我们知道，
if you were getting that 9 hours and if
如果你能睡够9个小时，甚至连续
we even gave you three nights of what we
三个晚上进行
call recovery sleep so we said okay now
所谓的“恢复性睡眠”，你的反应时间会有多快。 我说，好吧，
we get let's say 8 hours in bed for the
假设
next 3 days you're going to feel better
接下来三天你每天睡8小时，你会感觉好些，
and you'll probably feel more refreshed
也可能感觉更精神。
but those reaction times for the 7 hours
但是，睡7小时、
and the 5 hours and the 3H hour group
5小时和3小时那几组的反应时间并
didn't go back to the Baseline so it
没有恢复到基线水平。所以，你
takes more than one night night or one
需要不止一晚或一个
weekend of that recovery sleep to get
周末的恢复性睡眠才能
you back to your Baseline and so that's
恢复到基线水平。这就是
the bottom line that I tried to show my
我一直想向我的
athletes is that you can pay back sleep
运动员们解释的重点：你可以偿还睡眠
debt but it often can take more than
债，但这通常需要
just one day or one weekend of quality
不止一天或一个周末的优质
sleep how long does it take so my
睡眠。到底需要多久呢？我的
Studies have suggested multiple weeks uh
研究表明，几周的睡眠
more of your sleep debt than just a
比一
night or two nights of sleep the biggest
两晚的睡眠更有利于偿还睡眠债。最大的效果
bankr tends to be in the first week or
往往出现在最初的一两周，
two but obviously this depends on how
但这显然取决于
much more you're actually getting how
你实际的睡眠
you're timing that in your night but the
时间以及你如何安排睡眠。
bottom line is that if you can invest
总之，如果你能投入
maybe a week or maybe if you have a
一周的时间，或者如果你即将
vacation coming up and you do two weeks
休假，那就投入两周的时间，
that's going to be U the biggest impact
这将对
on paying back your sleep debt and if
偿还你的睡眠债产生最大的影响。 如果
you say hey that sounds like a long time
你说“嘿，听起来时间很长”，
Dr ma well even potentially like 5 days
嗯，马博士，即使是5天，
is one of my preliminary studies had
我的一项初步研究
suggested in professional baseball
表明，职业棒球
players even if it's 5 days of getting
运动员即使连续5天每天多
one additional hour of sleep that was
睡一个小时，也能
improve cognitive reaction time and also
提高认知反应时间和
processing speed in the athletes that
处理速度。也就是说，如果
you got six hours you went to seven if
你睡6个小时，就增加到7个小时；如果
you got seven hours you went to eight
你睡7个小时，就增加到8个
hours versus the athletes that just
小时。相比之下，那些
continue to get their normal sleep
继续正常睡眠的运动员则
and isn't cuz when you say the word debt
没有这种效果。这很有意思。我想我得弄明白“睡眠债”这个概念到底是什么，因为我想确保自己完全理解它的含义。因为当你提到“债”这个词时，
I assume it's kind of like I I owe
我以为就好像我欠了
the Sleep bank manager a couple of hours
睡眠银行经理几个小时似的。
um but but I I've kind of gone back on
嗯，我对“
forward on this idea of sleep debt I
睡眠债”这个概念一直摇摆不定。
think some people have told me that it's
有些人告诉我它是
real some people have told me that it's
真的，有些人告诉我它
not real um and I don't know where where
不是真的，我不知道
I should stand on it so if I if I
自己应该怎么看待它。所以，如果我还
haven't so for example I flew into La
没有…… 例如，我飞到洛杉矶的
first couple of nights my sleep wasn't
前几个晚上睡眠不太
great am I still but I had good sleep
好，现在还是这样吗？不过
last night am I still paying for it now
昨晚睡得不错，现在是不是还在为睡眠不足付出代价？
the way I explain the concept of sleep
我解释睡眠债的概念
dead is that your body requires a
是，你的身体
certain amount every single night again
每晚都需要一定量的睡眠。
we talked but individual variability but
我们之前也讨论过，睡眠时间因人而异。假设
let's just say you need 8 hours every
你每晚需要8小时睡眠，那么从
night and conceptually if you don't meet
概念上讲，如果你睡眠不足，就会
that 8 hours then you build up a debt so
积累睡眠债。
if you're only getting six hours a night
如果你每晚只睡6小时，那么
you now have two hours of debt built up
你就积累了2小时的睡眠债。
if you go Monday to Friday that's 5 days
如果你周一到周五，也就是5天，那么
now you have 10 hours built
你就积累了10小时的睡眠债。
up right two hours every night becomes
每晚2小时的睡眠债就变成了
10 hours and if you then sleep in on a
10小时。如果你
Saturday and you get let's just say 10
周六睡懒觉，睡了10个
hours of sleep you've paid back two of
小时，那么你就偿还了2小时的睡眠债，
those hours but you still have eight
但你仍然需要8
hours left to go and my buddy knows yes
小时的睡眠。我的朋友也知道这一点。所以，从
so conceptually that's the idea of
概念上讲，这就是
accumulating sleep debt I do stand in
睡眠债的积累。我的确
the camp that believes that that does
认为睡眠债会随着
accumulate over time we do think that
时间积累，但我们认为
you can pay back some of that debt on
你可以在短期内偿还一部分睡眠债。
like you said this past day or this past
就像你刚才说的，你损失了多少睡眠？ 过去一天、过去
week maybe this past month you should
一周，甚至过去一个月，你应该通过增加
pay that back with getting extra sleep
睡眠时间来弥补睡眠不足，
or we call Sleep extension we don't
我们称之为“睡眠延长”。我们并不
think that you can Surplus and Bank more
认为你可以“储存”更多睡眠，
and that you can pull from that in the
并在
future but we re recognize that if
未来随时调用，但我们确实认识到，如果
you've got insufficient sleep that if
你睡眠不足，如果将睡眠时间
you extend it over a couple of days
延长几天
maybe a couple weeks then you will see
甚至几周，
benefits in your reaction time in your
你的反应速度、
fatigue levels in your performance
疲劳程度和工作
outcomes and so we do recommend that as
表现都会有所改善。因此，我们推荐这种
a tool especially if you know that
方法，尤其是在你知道
you're going to have a day where you're
自己某天会
going to have sleep loss so it's a
睡眠不足的情况下。这是一种
strategy for example if you know okay in
策略。例如，如果你知道
a week I'm going to have a project and
下周要完成一个项目，而
that night night then what you can do in
那天晚上睡眠不足，那么你可以在项目开始前的
the days leading up to it is getting
几天里保证
sufficient sleep but arguably even more
充足的睡眠。更重要的是，
so that we know when it gets to that
我们知道，当真正开始
project the decrements that you'll
项目时，睡眠不足带来的负面影响
experience tend to be less robust than
会比你事先只睡了
was 5 hours so what evidence do you have
5个小时的情况要小得多。那么，有什么证据表明
that sleep debt is a real thing what's
睡眠债是真实存在的呢？你
the first thing that comes to mind so my
首先想到的是什么？
my what I've dedicated my career to is
我毕生致力于研究
trying to understand how to pay back
如何通过
sleep debt with sleep extension
延长睡眠时间来偿还睡眠债。
interventions so what that means is
这意味着，
typically I'm working with a number of
我通常会与一些
Collegiate athletes where many of them
大学运动员合作，他们中的许多人睡眠
are not getting what they need because
不足。
when we start these studies many of them
当我们开始这些研究时，他们中的许多人都
have high fatigue levels they are
处于高度疲劳状态，
reacting slowly we often see lapses in
反应迟缓，我们经常看到
their um their judgment and their
他们的判断力和
ability to ultimately perform and
最终
function which is what they consider
表现能力出现下降，而这正是他们所谓的“
their Baseline but then when we actually
基线”。但是，当我们
that debt by getting additional hours
通过增加睡眠时间来帮助他们偿还部分睡眠债时，
when we monitor the the differences that
我们会监测
can make over multiple weeks that's
几周内的变化。
where we see there's Improvement in the
我们发现，
reaction time their fatigue levels drop
他们的反应时间有所改善，疲劳程度有所下降，
their performance on the field improves
场上表现也有所提高。
and so we recognize what has changed in
因此，我们意识到，改变的关键
this is trying to pay back some of that
在于帮助他们偿还
accumulated debt when the rest of their
累积的睡眠债，同时保持他们其他
training has been held consistent where
训练的稳定。我们
we've been trying to maintain the rest
一直努力维持他们其他
of their their training which is key
训练的强度，这一点
which is the key point because in my
至关重要。因为在我
mind I go well maybe if you've got the
看来，如果
athlete to sleep well on that first
运动员在第一
night then when they've showed up to
晚睡得好，那么当他们第二天来
training they've trained a little bit
训练时，他们就会更加
harder they've built their muscles a
努力。 他们的肌肉增长得
little bit more they've had better
更多了，
recovery in their muscles so
肌肉恢复得也更好了，所以
then the next day the same thing happens
第二天同样的事情又发生了，
because they've slept so it's actually
因为他们睡了个好觉。实际上，是
just that they're training better which
他们训练得更好，才
is causing them to improve their that's
导致了他们的进步。这很
fair we we've tried to hold their
合理。我们努力保持他们的
training to be consistent and choosing
训练规律，并选择
periods where their training isn't going
训练量不会有
to vary significantly as well as you can
太大变化的时期。而且，你也可以说，随着
sometimes as the season goes on athletes
赛季的进行，运动员
get more fatigued more tired and that
会越来越疲劳，这
can be actually a decrement to how
实际上会降低
they'll perform so when we see the
他们的表现。所以，当我们看到
benefits come down the road as the
随着赛季的延长，这些益处逐渐显现时，
at least is some suggestion that the
至少表明
intervention of sleep while we also have
睡眠干预
getting actually were at least
确实
associated with these performance
与这些表现
outcomes because REM one of the key
结果相关。我们还测量了他们睡眠时间的增加量，因为快速眼动
things about REM sleep which is the sort
睡眠（REM）是
of final stage of sleep is that it helps
睡眠的最后一个阶段，它的关键作用之一是帮助
with Muscle Recovery uh deep sleep is
肌肉恢复。
actually deep sleep is where we uh deep
深度
sleep is where it's implied that there's
睡眠是指
more R Muscle Recovery regeneration
肌肉再生能力最强的阶段，
because there's the biggest pulse of
因为这是肌肉
growth hormone during your deep sleep so
生长最旺盛的时期。 深度睡眠期间的激素分泌情况，所以
to back up a bit you have light stages
稍微回顾一下，睡眠分为浅睡眠、深睡眠
sleep and then you have that rapid eye
和快速眼
movement sleep or when you dream that is
动睡眠（REM睡眠）。REM睡眠，也就是做梦的时候，通常
tends to be more associated with
与
consolidation of learning in memory and
记忆巩固和
skill consolidation so you go through
技能强化有关。你在
these Cycles during the night time about
夜间会经历这些睡眠周期，大约持续
90 to 120 minutes but the proportion
90到120分钟，但各个阶段的比例会随着时间
changes through the night the beginning
变化。夜里开始时，
of the night you get more of that deep
你会经历更多深度
sleep and then in the early morning
睡眠，而在
hours is when you get more of that REM
清晨，你会经历更多REM
sleep so you might have woken up in an
睡眠。所以你可能
earlier morning and had the recall of
早上醒得比较早，并且还记得
these vivid dreams it's because you
那些生动的梦境，这是因为你
often will be waking up from the that
经常会从
REM sleep yes that happened last night
REM睡眠中醒来。是的，昨晚就是这样。
actually CU I woke up suspiciously early
我醒得异常早，
for me so I woke up at about 5 or 6:00
大概五六点就醒了，然后就开始
and I was just kind of dipping in and
断断续续地做梦，
out of Dreams MH and were very vivid
而且梦境非常生动，
dreams that I can still remember now
我现在还记得。
yeah um so the muscle memory element of
嗯，那么，
all of this what is muscle memory and
肌肉记忆又是什么呢？它
how is that sort of implicated with
和
sleep so muscle memory there's different
睡眠有什么关系呢？肌肉记忆有很多种
types of memory and you need sleep think
类型。 你需要睡眠。把
of sleep as hitting that save button
睡眠想象成按下保存键，对吧？
learned new information learned a new
学习新知识或新
skill so that you can consolidate those
技能后，你需要睡觉，这样才能巩固
those uh those memories and be able to
记忆，以便
retrieve it later so I always use an
日后提取。所以我总是用“按下
analogy of hitting that save button
保存键”来打比方。
after you learn new material or learn a
学习新知识或
new skill set you need to go home and
新技能后，你需要回家
sleep so that it goes into long-term
睡觉，让知识长期
storage and that you can retrieve that
储存起来，以便第二天能够提取。如果
without that sleep we know that that
没有睡眠，我们知道，
groundwork for that new skill or that
新技能或
new memory is not going to be as strong
新记忆的基础就不会那么牢固。
and so in the context of students who
所以，对于
are trying to study for a test or an
正在备考的学生或
athlete that's trying to remember the
正在记忆战术手册的运动员来说，学习
material and have sleep that follows so
知识和睡眠之间需要留出一定的间隔，这样才能加强记忆与学习之间的
connections and also you mentioned when
联系。你刚才提到，你
athletes encouraging them to nap before
鼓励你的运动员在比赛前小睡一会儿。是的，我
word in the research that I was doing on
在研究
your work I think it's napino yes what's
你的工作时读到一个很有意思的词，我想是“napino”。“napino”是什么？“
a napino the nappuccino so this is a
nappuccino”（小睡片）。如果你想……，这是一个
useful tool if you're trying to have a
很有用的方法。 想要
temporary boost and aler and performance
暂时提神醒脑、提高工作效率，可以试试“小憩咖啡”（
so the nappuccino you go and take your
nappuccino）。先喝一杯你
favorite caffeinated beverage the
最喜欢的含咖啡因的饮料，
caffeine will start to kick in in about
大约15分钟后咖啡因就会开始起效。
15 minutes and you go and then take your
然后，你可以
20 to 30 minute power nap so if you're
小睡20到30分钟。如果你
able to fall asleep within that 5 to 10
能在咖啡因开始起效的5到10分钟内入睡，那么
after 20 to 30 minutes then bam both the
20到30分钟后醒来时，
caffeine will have kicked in and the
咖啡因和小憩的效果都会同时发挥作用。
there's research to show that that's
研究表明，这种方法
hours than if you only did the caffeine
比单独摄入咖啡因
alone or only did the power nap alone so
或单独小憩更能有效地提高几个小时的警觉性和工作效率。所以，“
the nappuccino is is a useful tool for
小憩咖啡”对于一些依赖咖啡因的人来说是一个很有用的工具，
some who who utilize caffeine and you
你
can partner that together with a short
可以把它和
20 to 30 minute nap so if I wanted to
20到30分钟的小睡结合起来。比如，如果我想
take a nap now I have an espresso and
小睡一会儿，我会先喝一杯浓缩咖啡，
then go and have my nap exactly yes the
然后再去小睡。没错，
cettas you do need to fall asleep within
你需要在小睡前入睡。
about 10 minutes or else the caffeine
大约10分钟，否则咖啡因
will start to come on board but if if
就会开始起作用。但如果
you do this in the late morning or early
你在上午晚些时候或下午早些时候这样做，
afternoon it can be a helpful tool so
它会是一个有用的工具，可以让
that you have a boost in your alertness
你
for a couple of hours and I grew up
在几个小时内保持清醒。我以前一直
thinking that naps didn't work because
认为午睡没用，因为当
the minute I learned about sleep and
我了解了睡眠和
these sleep cycles and that it takes I
睡眠周期，以及进入
to get into late stage sleep like the
深度睡眠（比如
Rems sleep the deep sleep I thought
快速眼动睡眠）需要45分钟、60分钟等等之后，我就想，
nap if I'm not going to get into deep or
如果我不能进入深度睡眠或
REM sleep so there's benefit of just
快速眼动睡眠，那么午睡15分钟或20分钟有什么意义呢？所以，
that 15minute nap you mentioned you want
你提到的15分钟午睡是有好处的。你想
to stay in lighter stages of sleep cuz
保持在较浅的睡眠阶段，因为
there's benefits of lighter stages of
浅睡眠阶段有很多好处，
sleep and that can give you that
它可以让你保持
alertness and performance boost even
清醒和提高表现。即使
when you're in lighter stages of sleep
在浅睡眠阶段，
you actually don't want to go into
你也不应该进入
deeper stages of sleep because when you
更深的睡眠阶段，因为当你
take the longer naps as I think you you
进行较长时间的午睡时——我想你
might have shared you you've taken the
可能说过你睡过
2-hour nap the three p you wake up and
2个小时的午觉—— 下午三点，你醒来后会感觉昏昏沉沉，精神萎靡，这种状态
groggy that's not a good state for you
不适合
to go out and then do you know work
出门，更别提之后还要工作了。
you want to be if you're a a basketball
如果你是篮球
player and have to go and play a game
运动员，需要去打比赛，这种状态对你来说也不理想。在
but those deeper stages you come out of
较深的睡眠阶段，你会摆脱所谓的“
what we call Sleep inertia with that
睡眠惯性”，这种
sluggishness and so it can also affect
昏沉感会影响
your sleep at night and make it harder
你晚上的睡眠，让你
to sleep subsequently so you actually
之后更难入睡。所以，你应该尽量保持在
want to stay in those lighter stages of
较浅的
sleep and keep those naps very short so
睡眠阶段，并且小睡时间要短。那么，
what's the maximum length that a nap
小睡的最长时长
should be I like 30 minutes okay yes so
应该是多少呢？我建议30分钟。
you can time that by setting an alarm if
你可以设置闹钟来计时。如果
it takes you 5 or 10 minutes to fall
你需要5到10分钟才能
asleep you can plan for that as well and
入睡，也可以提前计划好。
the setting alarm to wake yourself up 30
设置闹钟30
minutes later I think it's a great
分钟后叫醒自己，我认为这是一个很好的
strategy when again you don't get
策略。尤其是在你
sufficient sleep at night or you had
晚上睡眠不足，或者前一天晚上
poor sleep leading into that night and
睡眠质量不好，
you need a little bit of a boost later
需要提神的时候。
in the day what do you think of the
你觉得闹钟的
snooze button the snooze button I'm not
贪睡按钮怎么样？ 我不太喜欢闹钟的贪睡功能。
a huge fan of the snooze um I fully
嗯，我完全
understand why people love to hit the
理解为什么有些人喜欢按掉
snooze and then go back to bed uh and if
贪睡按钮然后继续睡。如果
you're someone who does that one of my
你也是这样，我的
suggestions is just to cut down so that
建议是减少
you only hit the snooze once 5 minutes
贪睡的次数，比如只按一次，五分钟
later start your day the reason why is
后起床。这样做的好处是，
morning hours if you can actually sleep
如果你能睡到
you have to wake up so for example if
起床时间，就能最大限度地延长清晨的快速眼动睡眠（REM睡眠）。举个例子，如果
you're someone who hits the snooze
你每隔
button five times every five minutes for
五分钟按一次贪睡按钮，持续
a half hour it means that you're having
半小时，那就意味着你
hour of your night versus if you just
前半夜的睡眠非常断断续续。而如果你能睡到自然醒，
way through and then maybe hit the
然后
snooze button just one time and then got
只按一次贪睡按钮，
yourself up to start your day it means
起床开始新的一天，就能多
minutes of Consolidated sleep likely
睡25分钟，而且很可能是快速眼动
that dreaming REM sleep that's so
睡眠，这
important for learning and memory and so
对学习和记忆至关重要。所以，这只是
you can make in terms of your morning
你早上起床方式的一个简单调整。
approach to maximizing what you get
充分利用
during the night so what's the what's
夜间睡眠时间，那么
the value in consolidating it versus
整合睡眠和
just having fragmented sleep yeah so
碎片化睡眠相比，其价值何在？
then if you're getting a lot of that REM
如果你
sleep in those early morning hours and
在清晨时段获得了大量的快速眼动睡眠（REM睡眠），但
you're snoozing you're going to be
你又在打盹，那么你就会
waking up and coming out of that REM
醒来，并结束REM
sleep so you likely are changing the
睡眠。这样一来，你在清晨时段的睡眠阶段可能会发生变化。
those early hours so you would then be
你会先是
awake and then probably going into
清醒，然后进入
lighter stages of sleep awake lighter
较浅的睡眠阶段，而不是像通常那样，从清醒到醒来都保持
a solid REM period all the way until you
稳定的REM睡眠。
wake up what's the cost of that so
这样做的代价是什么？
learning a memory and consolidation is
学习、记忆巩固无疑是
associated with that REM sleep and so
与REM睡眠密切相关的领域。正如
you want as we talked about it changes
我们之前讨论的，REM睡眠在夜间会发生变化，你当然希望
much as possible but you part have to
尽可能多地获得REM睡眠，但同时也要保证睡眠时长。
the most of it in the morning hours if
如果你在清晨时段获得了大量的REM睡眠，但你
you cut that short and either wake up
缩短了这段时间，要么
earlier or you're snoozing and you're
过早醒来，要么在打盹时
interrupting it you're not going to
中断了REM睡眠，那么你就无法
maximize the value you get of the hours
最大化REM睡眠的价值。
in rem okay so I just want to make sure
好的，我只是想确认一下。
that I those 25 minutes I give them to
我把那25分钟用来进行
REM sleep versus just giving them to
快速眼动睡眠（REM睡眠），而不是只让他们进入
little fragmented light sleep exactly so
零碎的浅睡眠。所以，
I'm better off just putting my alarm to
我最好把闹钟设在
the time that I actually have to get out
实际
of bed exactly just to maximize the
起床的时间，这样才能最大程度地保证快速眼动
amount of R sleep that I get to
睡眠，帮助我
consolidate my memories are you a
巩固记忆。你是个爱
snoozer no not really okay well I mean
赖床的人吗？不，其实不是。好吧，我的意思是，
we all have our moments but not really I
我们偶尔都会赖床，但我真的
can't remember the last time I pressed
记不清上次
pressed the snooze button but the thing
按贪睡按钮是什么时候了。
that I do and I'm not sure if this is a
我做的一件事，我不确定这算不算个
good idea or not is because I have told
好主意，就是我一直告诉
myself and I say told myself because I'm
自己——我说“告诉自己”，是因为我
quite conscious of the BS that I believe
很清楚自己
about myself but um I've told myself
对自己的一些想法——我告诉自己
that I'm like an alow chronotype or
我是个慢睡型的人，顺便说一句，
something which by the way I don't even
我甚至不
know if it's true and I don't know if
知道这是不是真的，我也不知道睡眠
chronotypes are true um and I typically
类型这种说法是不是真的。我通常
work quite late and I love working late
工作到很晚，而且我喜欢熬夜，因为我觉得晚上灵感
I get better ideas late I do my writing
更好，我写作也经常到很晚。
pretty late at night as well and so what
所以，
I've done in my life is I've basically
我这辈子一直在努力
made sure that I don't have any meetings
确保…… 我
or any engagements before 11:00 so even
11点之前没有任何会议或安排，所以即使是
like this podcast today started at 11:00
今天的播客也是11点开始的。
yes um basically nothing in my life
是的，基本上我生活中的所有事情都不到
starts till 11:00 for that very reason
11点才开始，原因就在于此。
just to because if I do end up staying
因为如果我
up a little bit late I want to be able
熬夜到很晚，我希望能够
to kind of sleep through without having
睡到自然醒，
to set an alarm and just wake up
而不用设闹钟。
naturally what do you think of that is
你觉得这样怎么样？这算不算不太理想？
that suboptimal no I think it's a great
不，我觉得这是个很棒的
strategy so there are chronotypes where
策略。
you've mentioned you're more of an
你提到过你更像个夜猫子，
evening owl you go to bed later you like
喜欢晚睡
to wake up later as a natural
晚起，这是自然而然的
predilection is is that real or I just
偏好，是真的吗？还是我只是在为
myself this is justifying myself no
自己找借口？不，
there is a natural tendency for some to
有些人天生就
feel like they are evening owls and
觉得自己是夜猫子，而有些
there's others who feel like they do
人则觉得自己
much better in the morning so they go to
早上状态更好，所以他们
bed earlier they wake up earlier they're
早睡早起，
more productive in the morning those are
早上效率更高，这些人就是早起
are morning Larks and then there is a
鸟。还有一部分人介于两者之间，
that don't strongly lean one way or
没有明显的倾向性。
another but really what you're doing is
但实际上，你…… 这样做就是让你
you're you're making your sleep work to
的睡眠适应
your your chronotype and to your
你的生物钟类型，并发挥你的
advantage where you do feel like you're
优势，让你感觉
more productive in the evenings and then
晚上效率更高。然后
you want to be able to maximize your
你想最大限度地利用
sleep waking up without an alarm and
睡眠时间，不用闹钟就能醒来，晚点
starting your day later I think that's
开始新的一天。我认为这是
like a great strategy because a lot of
一个很好的策略，因为很多
people aren't able to have that
人无法拥有这种
flexibility and so Society often will
灵活性。所以社会常常
force particularly the night owls onto
强迫，尤其是夜猫子，
an earlier schedule where you have to
早起，
wake up whether to go to work or other
无论是为了上班、履行其他
obligations or kids earlier Point yeah
义务还是照顾孩子。没错，
and and then you're cutting your sleep
然后就像你提到的，你就会缩短睡眠时间，比如
school and then we're getting these um
上学的时候。然后我们就会遇到这些问题，
and then you're on a schedule that
你的作息时间
doesn't work synergistically with what
与
your chronotype is they should do some
你的生物钟类型并不协调。应该对学生进行一些
studies on kids in school and like
研究，比如
Disobedience and ability to pay
不服从、
attention and do homework in grades
注意力集中和完成作业的能力，以及这些因素对成绩的影响。说
because honestly I was so useless in
实话，我以前在学校里很差劲。我
now I'm not entirely sure here because I
现在真的很难确定，因为我在
30 years old so part of me thinks I've
30岁左右被诊断出患有注意力缺陷多动障碍（ADHD）。所以我觉得我可能只是…… 我的
just got like a very active brain and
大脑非常活跃，而
part part of having an active brain
活跃的大脑
meant that late at night I was Finding
意味着我经常在深夜
ways to stimulate it by playing Video
玩电子游戏等方式来刺激它，这
Games Etc so that might just be the
可能是
reason but the other reason might be
原因之一。但另一个原因可能是
that I'm an Al Chron type and I found it
我属于“懒惰型”人，我发现早上
really hard to get up at like 7:30 to
7:30起床去学校真的很难，因为要在
get to go to school by sort of 8:30ish
8:30左右到校对
and so I would miss school I would show
我来说太难了，所以我经常旷课，到校时
up knacked I would sleep in lessons um
筋疲力尽，或者上课睡觉。
and I feel like school just starts way
我觉得学校
too early for kids it's a ongoing uh
对孩子们来说上课时间太早了，
it's an ongoing problem and actually in
这是一个长期存在的问题。实际上，一个
a very interesting way there has been a
非常有趣的现象是，
change to school start times
学校的上课时间已经发生了变化，
particularly in California um this this
尤其是在加利福尼亚州。今年
year was the first year that school
是加州
start start times for high schools and
高中和
for middle schools was shifted much
初中上课时间首次大幅推迟的一年，
later because there are studies to show
因为有研究表明，
that our when our students are better
当学生
rested they have higher attendance rates
休息充足时，他们的出勤率更高，
their GPA and grades are much higher
GPA和成绩也更高，
there's less mental health issues um
心理健康问题更少，
there's less car accidents and so this
交通事故也更少。
these Studies have um been over the last
这些研究在过去
decade and longer in which they have
十年甚至更长时间里一直在
built evidence to help make decisions to
积累证据，以支持这一观点。
start school time later um and that is
推迟上课时间的决定，
in California been enacted this year and
加州今年已经实施，
some other states are starting to follow
其他一些州也开始效仿。
suit but to your point what makes it
但正如你所说，真正的
challenging is that at the age of high
挑战在于，
school many of those body clocks are
高中生的生物钟会发生
shifted and so students St want to an
改变。
adolescence go to bed later and wake up
青春期的学生自然而然地会晚睡晚起，这是
later naturally that's just how our
我们
sleep changes through the life cycle but
生命周期中睡眠时间自然变化的过程。但
when they stay up late and then we cut
如果他们熬夜，然后我们又
their sleep short by forcing them to get
强迫他们早起上学，缩短他们的睡眠时间，就会造成
insufficient sleep and that builds like
睡眠不足，形成
a sleep debt and so they're not setting
睡眠债，从而影响他们
themselves up for success in school for
在学校的
learning and memory so that's where
学习和记忆。因此，
again there's more evidence of if we can
有更多证据表明，如果我们能
shift the school start time get these
推迟上课时间，让
students to have a little bit more sleep
学生们多睡一会儿，
they ultimately are better prepared for
他们最终会更好地为
school come to school have less uh car
上学做好准备，减少
accidents and are just healthier
交通事故，成为更健康的
students do you think there's anything
学生。你认为
parents need to know about sleep when it
家长在孩子睡眠方面需要了解些什么？
sleep hygiene with their children I
我
think it's important for parents to
认为家长应该从孩子很小的时候就
start at the early early years of
开始
instilling good sleep habits a good
培养良好的睡眠习惯和规律的作息。
sleep routine and giving their their
他们应该让
children the tools and skills to be able
孩子们掌握必要的工具和技能，
to make sure that it's a priority as
确保他们在
they go through early childhood into
幼儿期到
adolescence and hopefully then sets
青春期都能把睡眠放在首位，并希望这能帮助他们在成年后也把睡眠放在首位。
priority for their adult life um I'm a
我
young parent myself I just had uh my
自己也是一位年轻的父母，我的
first son and so um I recognize and can
第一个儿子刚刚出生，所以我能理解并体会
empathize with the TR the struggles of
到TR（可能是指某个品牌或机构）在孩子很小的时候难以保证
getting sufficient sleep when they're
充足睡眠的困境。
early age I think would be incredibly
我认为，从小培养他们正确的睡眠习惯非常有
helpful to also just change culturally
帮助，同时也能改变我们
how we think about sleep because so many
对睡眠的固有观念。因为
of us now have never learned about sleep
我们中的很多人直到成年才开始了解睡眠的重要性，
for or what we should do until you're an
或者应该如何安排睡眠。
adult but if we can make that change
如果我们能更早地做出改变，
earlier on I think we're going to have
我相信我们会拥有更
healthier kids better families um who
健康的孩子、更幸福的家庭，以及更多
are better rested and and also just this
休息充足的孩子。而且，
generation where we recognize this is so
我们这一代人应该认识到睡眠的
important that we shouldn't sacrifice it
重要性，不要因为忽视它而牺牲睡眠，否则就无法
disservice to letting us be the best
让自己成为最好的自己。
that we can possibly be how old is your
你
son 11 months 11 months so how are you
儿子多大了？11个月。你
sleeping oh I transparently am quite
睡得怎么样？哦，说实话，我
tired okay I I as a yeah new Young mom
挺累的。 作为一个新手妈妈，
also um I don't have the ideal sleep
嗯，我的睡眠并不像我理想中的那样充足。
that I know I would love um it's a for a
我知道睡眠时间很
short time but I'm trying to be
短，但我正在尝试运用
with some of the tools that we've talked
一些我们之前讨论过的技巧，比如利用小睡来改善睡眠。
when for example I do have to still wake
例如，当我晚上不得不
up during the night time to tend to him
醒来照顾宝宝时，我会尽量利用小睡。
um and you know the early morning starts
而且，你知道，清晨的作息时间
are not always consistent so my sleep
并不总是规律的，所以我的睡眠
schedule is not always consistent so you
时间也不总是固定的。
know going back to those three buckets
回到
we talked about earlier like if I don't
我们之前讨论的那三个方面，如果我无法
get the full duration that I want then
获得理想的睡眠时长，那么
how do I maximize the quality right I've
我该如何最大限度地提高睡眠质量呢？我已经
optimized my sleep environment I try to
优化了我的睡眠环境，并尝试
have a process to wind down at nighttime
在晚上养成放松的习惯。
sleep schedule is another area that you
睡眠时间也是另一个需要改进的地方，
can still work on when for example you
比如，当你
may not be getting the duration um so
无法获得足够的睡眠时。
these are strategies that I try to
这些都是我尝试
employ when I know that I um also am a
采用的策略，因为我知道自己还在不断进步，
work in progress and trying to get the
努力获得
best sleep possible Once Upon a Time if
尽可能好的睡眠。很久以前，如果
you had a business idea it was
你有一个创业想法，
exceptionally difficult to get going but
启动起来会非常困难，但
now in the age of Shopify it is
现在情况不同了。 在 Shopify 时代，这变得
exceptionally easy as many of you will
异常简单，正如你们许多人
know Shopify are a sponsor of this
所知，Shopify 是这项服务的赞助商。
podcast if you don't know Shopify it's
如果你还不了解 Shopify，它是
an exceptionally simple web platform for
一个极其简单的网络平台，适合
anybody that's got an idea that wants to
任何有想法并想
transact on a global scale so things
在全球范围内进行交易的人。
like these conversation cards which we
比如我们销售的这种对话卡片，就是
sell we've sold using Shopify and it
用 Shopify 卖的，
only took us a couple of clicks to get
只需点击几下就能
going so why did we choose Shopify for a
上线。我们选择 Shopify 的
number of reasons but I think one of the
原因有很多，但我认为其中一个最
big ones which goes and appreciated is
重要的原因，也是我们非常欣赏的，是
their checkout system converts 36%
它的结账系统
better compared to other platforms and
比其他平台转化率高出 36%。为了帮你
the cost for you if you go to
省钱，我来告诉你：如果你访问
shopify.com Bartlet you'll be able to
shopify.com Bartlet，就可以
$1 a month I've seen Shopify completely
每月花 1 美元试用 Shopify。我亲眼见证了 Shopify 彻底
change people's lives and for many of
改变了人们的生活，
you I think it could change yours what
我相信它也能改变你们中的许多人的生活。
studies that you're you're most proud of
你还有哪些案例研究让你感到自豪，
or that were most pivotal in shaping
或者对
your thinking about sleep I mentioned
你关于睡眠的思考影响最大？我之前提到过
the Philadelphia Eagles back in 2017 and
2017 年的费城老鹰队，我曾
tried to help them educate their players
试图帮助他们教育球员如何更好地安排
about sleep how to have a more strategic
睡眠，如何更有策略地
approach to their wind down routine to
安排放松时间，以及
thinking about how they're integrating
如何将
sleep into their training practices and
睡眠融入到训练中。 实践和
thinking about ultimately how they
思考最终如何
travel and and having for example
旅行，例如制定
strategies to minimize jet lag when
策略来最大限度地减少
you're Crossing time zones and having to
跨越时区和
play in different locations than the
在不同地点比赛时的时差反应。请给
give me some of those then so some the
我一些建议。
tips you'd give me someone that travels
你会给经常旅行的人一些建议吗？
a lot yeah um pre- during and post
嗯，旅行前、旅行中和旅行后
travel yeah what should I be thinking
应该考虑什么？是的，
a a game plan for every trip I think
每次旅行都要制定计划。我认为
most people have no strategies in place
大多数人
when they travel they just get onto an
旅行时没有策略，他们只是登上
airplane get to a new location and try
飞机，到达一个新的地方，然后
to adjust when they get there that is
试图适应。这
not really a great strategy you want to
并不是一个好策略。你
have at least a pre-flight strategy
至少需要飞行前策略、
inflight strategy and post-flight
飞行中策略和飞行后
strategies because that will set
策略，因为这将帮助你更好地
yourself up better to minimize jet lag
减少时差反应
also travel fatigue and ultimately then
和旅行疲劳，最终更快地适应。
be able to acclimate faster if you're
如果你要
Crossing multiple time zones before
跨越多个时区，飞行前
pre-flight try not to panic pack I know
尽量不要慌张地打包。我知道
all of us do do Panic packing right
我们都会在睡前、登机前慌张地打包。
a flight um so you want to try and be
所以你要尽量有
strategic and pack early you want to get
策略地提前打包。
at least why do I want to not panic pack
至少，我不想慌张。
because most people will Panic pack the
大多数人会在
night before they they have a flight and
航班起飞前一晚慌慌张张地收拾行李，
then they'll cut their sleep short so
然后睡眠时间就会大大缩短，可能
they'll get only say 5 hours of sleep
只睡5个小时，
because they're staying up late trying
因为他们熬夜
to pack everything and get ready for
打包所有东西，准备迎接清晨的
that early morning flight or for the
航班或
next day well I I pack the morning of
第二天的行程。而我会在出发当天早上收拾
travel so okay but I'm I'm out here in
行李。好吧，我现在在
La for I'm out here for 2 weeks and I
洛杉矶，要待两周，我只
packed a carryon carryon suitcase okay
带了一个随身行李箱。你
cuz I so look at what I'm wearing I wear
看我穿的，我
just the same outfit every day so I have
每天都穿同样的衣服，所以我的
like the same outfit um but I pack
衣服都差不多。但我会在去
literally an hour before I go to the
机场前一个小时才开始收拾行李。
airport okay okay so but you're right it
好吧，你说得对，这确实会
does cut my sleep because I could have
减少我的睡眠时间，因为我本来可以早点
been in bed whether it's beginning of
上床睡觉的。不管是
the day or the end of the day if it's
早上还是晚上，如果这
affecting then the duration of your
影响了你的
sleep I would recommend trying to a
睡眠时长，我建议你
little more strategic and do it a day
更有计划地安排，
before two days before don't pain it
提前一天或两天收拾行李。
pack number two try to get at least
第二点，尽量保证至少
those seven hours if not
7个小时的
your your amount of sleep that makes you
睡眠，这样你才能
feel like you're functioning and
感觉精力充沛，
Performing well um at least a day if not
状态良好。 至少要提前一天，甚至
two days if you get insufficient sleep
两天睡眠不足，否则
before you get onto an airplane jet lag
登机前的时差反应
will be worse and that travel fatigue
会更严重，旅途疲劳
can feel much more robust and you're
感也会更加强烈，而且你
more likely to have the quas on in the
很可能在
airport which is going to destroy the
机场就出现呼吸困难，这会彻底毁掉你的旅行体验。
whole thing for for you so those are
所以，
depending on where you're going you can
根据你的目的地，你可以在飞行前做一些事情来
actually start to adjust your body clock
调整你的生物钟。比如，
here in the US if you're in the west
假设美国
coast and you're going to the east coast
西海岸和东海岸有3个小时的时差，
three time zones you can actually start
你就可以提前
to go to bed a half hour early wake up a
半小时睡觉，提前半小时起床，坚持
half hour early do that for two or 3
两到三天，
days and and get sunlight in the morning
并且早上要多晒太阳，
because that sunlight reinforces to your
因为阳光有助于
brain to start to shift that body clock
大脑调整生物钟。
so if you can do that a day before 2
如果你能在出发前一天、
days before maybe 3 days before when you
两天甚至三天就开始这样做，那么当你
actually get to the new location you
到达目的地时，
don't have to shift your body clock
你的生物钟就不需要再调整
three time zones you've already shifted
三个时区了，因为你已经调整了
it one time zone or two time zones
一个或两个时区。
because the rule of thumb is for every
因为一般来说，每
time zone you cross it takes about a day
跨越一个时区，大约需要……
to re acclimate even if you feel better
即使第一天感觉好多了，也需要一天时间来重新适应时差。
after the first day usually jetti feels
通常来说，抵达目的地的
the worst in that first day when you
第一天时差反应最严重，因为
arrive um but physiologically you
生理上你还
haven't really adjusted fully even if
没有完全适应，即使过了
it's over you know a couple of days so
几天也是如此。
that's the rule of thumb so those are
这是个经验法则。所以，
some things pre-flight you can do when
飞行前你可以做以下几件事：
you're in Flight you want to hydrate
飞行途中要不断补充水分，
throughout the flight because
因为
dehydration can worsen jet lag you want
脱水会加剧时差反应；要
to think about getting onto the new time
考虑调整作息时间，适应新的时
zone schedule so again depending on
区；根据
which direction you're flying and how
你的飞行方向和
many times when you're Crossing you want
穿越次数，
to start to synchronize perhaps like
开始调整作息，比如调整
when you're actually sleeping or some of
睡眠时间或
your meal times so that you're getting
用餐时间，让自己适应新的时
onto that schedule and then you partner
区；此外，还可以
that with for example building a travel
准备一个旅行
sleep kit I'm a huge fan of investing in
睡眠套装。我非常推荐投资一些
sleep tools that will help you sleep
睡眠工具，它们可以帮助你在
when you need to in non- ideal
不理想的
situations whether you're on the plane
环境下入睡，比如在飞机上想
and now trying to take a nap or shift
小睡一会儿或者调整
your sleep schedule then you actually
睡眠时间。
have an eye mask and ear plugs you have
有了眼罩、耳塞、
noise cancelling headphones you have
降噪耳机、
your own travel pillow you have the
旅行枕，以及其他
tools with you to S drugs sorry sleeping
助眠工具，你就能轻松入睡。 抱歉，关于
medication okay so some uh medications
安眠药，好吧，有些药物
can be helpful like melatonin
可能有用，比如褪黑素，
particularly if you're trying to advance
尤其是在你想提前
your clock has um evidence that it can
生物钟的时候。有证据表明，如果
quickly when you're trying to advance
你想提前
your clock earlier would you recommend
生物钟，褪黑素可以帮助你更快地调整。你会推荐
it to athletes um it I would say if it's
给运动员吗？嗯，我会说，如果
something that you've used before and
你以前用过，而且
you know that you don't experience some
知道自己不会出现某些
of the side effects it could be a useful
副作用，那么它可能是一个有用的
tool so melatonin while it's one of the
工具。褪黑素是
most commonly used supplements and sleep
最常用的补充剂和助眠
aids there are still side effects that
剂之一，但仍然有一些副作用需要
to be wary of so specifically for
注意。特别是对于
athletes too you can feel more groggy
运动员来说，服用后醒来可能会感觉更昏昏沉沉、反应
and sluggish when you wake up from it um
迟钝。
in the US and so you don't always know
在美国，它不受FDA监管，所以你并不总是知道
what's actually in those supplements so
这些补充剂里到底有什么成分。因此，
for my lead athletes they use what's
我的顶级运动员会使用
called NSF Sports certified versions um
所谓的NSF运动认证版本，这些版本受到
they're just there's more um regulation
更多监管。
around them but in for the for the you
但对于
know everyday person you know there's a
普通人来说，有一项
study where they looked at the amount of
研究调查了
melatone that was actually in a variety
褪黑素的摄入量。 实际上，很多
of these supplements and it was a wide
这类补充剂的含量都存在这个问题，而且含量
range from over 400% of what was on the
差异很大，从超过标签标示含量的400%到
uh under 100% of what they actually
低于100%都有。
indicated so there's a wide range of
所以，补充剂的实际含量差异很大。
supplement but it can help particularly
不过，它确实能帮上忙，尤其是在
when you're on travel with um re
旅行途中，比如重新
acclimating my team here we most of them
适应环境的时候。我们团队的大部分成员在
use a certain app when we travel and it
旅行时都会使用一款应用程序，它
just tells you basically you say where
基本上会告诉你目的地，然后
you're going and then it'll tell you
告诉你
what time to eat what time not to eat
什么时候该吃饭，什么时候不该吃饭
Etc so you can get aligned with that
等等。这样你就可以根据目的地调整
with your destinations like circadian
自己的作息时间，就像调整昼夜
rhythm I guess so we'll link below one
节律一样。我会在下面附上
of the apps that our team use we're not
我们团队使用的应用程序的链接。我们
affiliated with them in any way but
和他们没有任何关联，但
we're flying out here I know will and my
我们这次要飞过来，我知道我的
team sent me a screenshot and said Steve
团队成员给我发了一张截图，说：“史蒂夫，
this is what time you need to be eating
这是你需要吃饭的时间，
and everything cuz we're going to La so
因为我们要去洛杉矶。”所以，这款应用程序
it's been super helpful for all of us I
对我们所有人来说都非常有帮助。
I'll link that below because I know some
我会在下面附上链接，因为我知道有些
people are going to be wondering what
人会想知道
apps they should be using so we're in
他们用的是什么应用程序。 我们应该使用……所以我们现在在
the flight we've got our postt trvel
飞机上，带上了
flight kit with the ey masks and all
旅行套装，
those kinds of things in we've got our
里面有眼罩之类的东西，还有我们的
app is we're
应用程序，确保
hydrated um noise cancelling headphones
水分充足，以及降噪耳机。
thinking about while we're traveling
旅行途中还有什么需要注意的吗？比如在
plane so we talked about hydration minim
飞机上，我们之前讨论过要多喝水，尽量少喝含酒精
Al and caffeine or eliminating entirely
和咖啡因的饮料，或者干脆完全戒掉，
because that can also potentially worsen
因为这些都可能加重
um jet lag and or make it more difficult
时差反应，或者让
to sleep when you're actually trying to
你到达目的地后更难入睡。
when you arrive and again seeking light
再次强调，要多晒太阳，
that is the most powerful signal to your
这是向大脑发出的最强信号，
brain to help shift your body clock also
有助于调整你的生物钟。还要
bringing sunglasses so that you actually
带上太阳镜，这样你就可以
avoid sunlight at certain times because
在某些时间段避免阳光直射，因为
your body can respond differently
你的身体反应会
depending again on your home location
根据你的居住地
and how many time zones youve crossed so
和跨越的时区数量而有所不同。
there's certain times that these apps
有些应用程序
can be helpful that will likely tell you
会很有帮助，它们会告诉你哪些时间段不宜
you don't want to get sunlight during
晒太阳。
these hours and so you want to be
所以你需要
strategic about that and just make sure
合理安排时间，确保
you have sunglasses so that you can
带上太阳镜，这样你
still go about your day but trying to
仍然可以正常活动，但尽量
minimize that sun exposure um getting
减少阳光照射。 晒太阳、
well rested and getting sufficient sleep
充分休息和保证充足睡眠，
even if it might be a little bit more
即使睡眠可能比平时
fragmented than usual just giving
断断续续一些，也要给
yourself at least a day to acclimate so
自己至少一天的时间来适应。所以
that I would recommend not scheduling
我建议不要把
your most important meetings right when
最重要的会议安排在
you get in or in that first day for
抵达时或第一天。对于
athletes they don't want to do maximal
运动员来说，他们不应该进行高强度
exercise because there's a risk that
训练，因为
that jetl could increase injury in that
时差可能会增加
acute period so you want your body clock
急性期受伤的风险。你需要让你的生物钟重新
to be able to readjust and then using
调整。然后，要
caffeine and power nap strategically so
策略性地使用咖啡因和小睡。
for example our afternoon 1 to 4:00 is
例如，下午1点到4点
typically when we have this dip in our
通常是我们注意力下降的时候。
alertness now when you get to a new time
当你到达一个新的时
zone that can occur at a different time
区时，这种情况可能会在一天中的不同时间出现，
point in the day but strategically then
但
you can use CA and and uh Power naaps to
你可以策略性地使用咖啡因和小睡来
be able to help you through those lulls
帮助你度过这些低谷期。至于
about sex sleep and sex in bed and that
性生活，在床上进行性生活怎么样？就是这样，
is it because I think so many people
因为我认为很多人犯的
actually make the mistake of being in
错误是，在醒着的时候躺在
bed and being on their computer on their
床上玩电脑、
phone doing other work while they're
手机或其他工作，
awake and that actually helps strengthen
这实际上会加强你们之间的
that connection that when you're in bed
联系。 你躺在床上，却
you're awake and your brain will start
醒着，你的大脑会开始将
to associate that so sleep and sex are
这种状态与睡眠联系起来，所以
all that you want in bed everything else
床上你只想睡觉和性爱，其他一切都
should be outside so when we talked
应该在床外进行。我们之前讨论过的
about that wind down routine or that
放松程序，或者说那些让你
racing mind all that should happen
思绪纷乱的事情，都应该在
outside of bed because you want to
床外进行，因为你需要
actually tease apart that Association
打破
that your brain is making of being awake
大脑将清醒状态
in bed and that will be one small
与在床上睡眠联系起来的习惯。这是一个
adjustment that's helpful to to get
有助于
better rest at night but will will sex
改善夜间睡眠的小调整。但是，性爱究竟会
improve or hurt my sleep I'm thinking
改善还是损害我的睡眠呢？我在想，
you know CU I'm really trying to get out
你知道，我真的很想弄清楚，和
like should you be in bed with someone
别人同床共枕是否合适？
sleep with someone and does sex have an
和别人同床共枕真的能改善睡眠吗？性爱会对
impact on your sleep cuz I you know
睡眠产生影响吗？
with you in bed because their movements
因为就我个人经验而言，我觉得如果睡前做爱，我会睡得更好。虽然关于睡眠和性爱的研究文献不多，但我想说的是，和伴侣同床共枕肯定会对睡眠产生影响，因为他们的动作会
can affect your sleep if they snore that
影响你的睡眠。如果他们打鼾，那就
can very much affect your waking up
更容易导致你夜间醒来。至于
know with sex I think that that is
性爱，我认为……
something anecdotally some people will
有些人
definitely say it helps them to be able
确实会说，睡得更香更有助于他们
to consolidate their sleep and they feel
巩固睡眠，感觉睡眠
like the quality is better um but I
质量也更好。但是，目前并
don't think there's a lot of great
没有很多高质量的
studies that are are being funded for
研究获得资助。关于睡眠，人们
popular question you typically get asked
最常问的问题是什么？最常见的问题
question is napping which we've
是午睡，我们之前
discussed keep them short 20 to 30
讨论过，午睡时间要短，20到30
minutes I I get asked a fair amount
分钟即可。我还经常被问到睡过头会不会有害，
about can you oversleep so no we don't
所以我们
think you really you should you can
认为不应该睡过头。
overs sleep when some people say they
有些人说他们睡了
get say 9 hours or 10 hours and feel
9个小时或10个小时，但感觉
much more groggy it's because often
更昏昏沉沉，这通常是因为
they've shifted their sleep schedule or
他们的睡眠时间被打乱了，或者
they have an accumulated debt that say
他们之前积累了睡眠不足，
built up and then they're finally
现在终于可以
allowing their body to relax and so now
放松一下了。
that they're they're they don't have the
他们不再受
their day or their work that can read I
白天或工作中的各种刺激活动的影响，所以睡得更香。我
read I didn't read a study one of my
读过一篇
podcast guests told me that there is a
播客嘉宾的文章，他说
harm to oversleeping but I think from
睡过头有害，但我没读到相关的研究。不过，根据
what I managed to
我了解到的情况……
ascertain the studies they were citing
他们引用的研究
just proved that people who sleep for
只是证明，睡眠时间长达
like 10 or 11 hours
10到11个小时的人
typically have a higher risk of um
通常
disease and mental health but then it's
患病和心理健康风险更高，但
hard to establish cause and effect
很难确定因果关系，
because if you're in bed for 11 hours
因为如果你在床上躺了11个小时，
maybe you're a depressed and B one would
你可能患有抑郁症，而且人们会
assume you're exercising and moving a
认为你的运动量和活动量会
little bit less so you probably got a
减少，所以你可能有
lot of like cardiovascular issues yes so
很多心血管疾病。是的，
there are studies of looking at the more
有一些研究关注
extremes of Less hours of sleep and then
睡眠时间过短和
even more hours of sleep like the 10
睡眠时间过长这两个极端情况，比如10个
hours and obviously there can be other
小时。显然，睡眠时间过长的人可能还伴有其他
comorbid conditions uh that go along
合并症，
with individuals like who sleep much
就像
longer you mentioned you can sleep much
你提到的，有些人睡眠时间
longer because of depression or other um
过长是因为抑郁症或其他
chronic health issues and so um that's a
慢性健康问题。所以，这是
different context of thinking about
思考睡眠过多的一个不同角度。
oversleeping I think in the question I
我
typically get is oh I slept one night of
经常被问到的问题是：“我有一晚睡了
10 hours and I feel worse so I'm never
10个小时，感觉更糟了，所以我
going to do that again and that's
再也不会这样做了。”这
actually not true right I think we want
其实是不对的。我认为我们应该养成
to have just more consistent hours that
更规律的睡眠习惯，
are timed so you're not having a shift
这样你的睡眠时间就不会出现波动。
in the bedtime and wake Time by like
就寝时间和起床时间比平时晚
three hours later um because that could
三个小时左右，这可能是
be why you're having that grogginess
你
when you wake up not because you got the
醒来时感到昏昏沉沉的原因，不是因为你睡够了
10 hours but because you're waking up up
10个小时，而是因为你
now at 11:00 a.m. instead of your
现在早上11点才起床，而不是
typical you know 8:00 a.m. wake up time
通常的8点。
um you could be more dehydrated because
由于睡眠时间延长，你可能会更加脱水。
of that longer time um snoring is one
打鼾是
that I get asked a fair amount about is
我经常被问到的问题，
you know is it completely benign and I
它是否完全无害。我的
would say if you're snoring you should
建议是，如果你打鼾，你应该
go talk with your primary care doctor
去看你的家庭医生，
and you should potentially ask about
并咨询是否需要
getting a sleep study there is Sleep
进行睡眠监测。睡眠
Disorders like obstructive sleep apnea
障碍，比如我们之前提到的阻塞性睡眠呼吸暂停，
we mentioned before that's incredibly
非常
common and that's when that Airway has
常见。阻塞性睡眠呼吸暂停是指气道
partial or full collapse and can lead to
部分或完全塌陷，会导致
very fragmented sleep so you can wake up
睡眠断断续续，所以你醒来后
not refreshed because you really didn't
不会感到精神焕发，因为你
get quality sleep during the night time
夜间睡眠质量很差。
and snoring I think in our society has
我认为在我们的社会中，打鼾已经
become just an accepted Norm that can
成为一种被接受的常态，
happen as you get older but that is not
随着年龄的增长可能会发生，但这并非总是如此。 睡眠呼吸暂停是
always the case that it is uh a benign a
一种
benign symptom and so um making sure
良性症状，所以，确保
that you talk to your primary care
你咨询你的家庭
doctor and potentially get a sleep study
医生，并可能需要进行睡眠研究，
I think is incredibly important is sleep
我认为这非常重要。睡眠
apnea the the most common um disease
呼吸暂停是最常见的
disorder you see yes yes it
疾病之一，是的，它
isapa can be incredibly common I believe
非常常见。我相信在
the ages of 30 to 70 and so that as you
30到70岁的人群中，大约有26%的人患有睡眠呼吸暂停，也就是说，大约
imagine that's like one in four
四分之一的人都患有此病。
individuals but many individuals don't
但是，许多人直到成年后，甚至到了60到70岁，才
actually get tested or diagnosed and
接受检查、诊断和
then treated until they're way into
治疗。
their 6070s so with asleep apnea often
患有睡眠呼吸暂停的
times people will not wake up refreshed
人通常醒来后不会感到精神焕发，
they will often feel tired in the
白天经常感到疲倦，
daytime they may have a lot of caffeine
可能需要摄入大量咖啡因
or have to rely on power kns to keep
或依赖能量饮料来保持
their alertness up a lot of individuals
清醒。许多人
will have early morning Awakenings so in
会在
those 3 4 5:00 in the morning they'll
凌晨3点到5点之间
wake up and not realize why they're
醒来，却不知道自己为什么
waking up frequently snoring can be very
醒来。打鼾也很
common if you've ever had a bed partner
常见，如果你曾经有过打鼾的经历的话。 如果你的同床伴侣或
or a roommate and they've ever noted
室友注意到
that you stop breathing or pause
你呼吸暂停、
breathing or gasp and choke those are
呼吸停止或喘息、甚至窒息，这些都
very suggestive that you might have
强烈暗示你可能患有
sleep apnea um and again it is
睡眠呼吸暂停。睡眠呼吸暂停
incredibly common but very manageable so
非常常见，但很容易控制。所以，如果
if you your bed partner your your
你的同床伴侣或
roommate snore just uh suggest to have
室友打鼾，
um I would suggest they go see their
我强烈建议他们去看
primary care doctor and typically is it
家庭医生。通常来说，
people that are slightly overweight that
略微超重的人
are more likely and susceptible to
更容易患
having sleep apnea yes yes a lot of
睡眠呼吸暂停吗？是的，很多
individuals who are overweight or obese
超重或肥胖的人
um will be more at risk for Sleep back
更容易患睡眠呼吸暂停。
as you imagine the collapse of the
正如你所想，
airway typically is here around the neck
气道塌陷通常发生在颈部附近，
and so more weight um typically is is
所以体重增加通常
not helpful for for apne but you can
不利于睡眠呼吸暂停的发生。但即使是
also be a very fit healthy young
非常健康强壮的年轻人也可能患上睡眠呼吸暂停。
individual so I work with Elite athletes
我与精英运动员合作，
and I have a number of my professional
我的许多职业
athletes who again are young healthy
运动员都是年轻健康的
males but their Anatomy is just more
男性，但他们的身体结构更
susceptible for this condition what are
容易患上这种疾病。
excuses that you hear from people I
人们经常会找各种借口，比如“我
don't have enough time
没时间”，是的，
yeah I don't have enough time to sleep
我没有。 有足够的时间睡觉？
okay I don't have enough time to sleep
好吧，我没有足够的时间睡觉，
and what do you think of that one uh I
你觉得呢？嗯，我
don't think that that's true I think we
不认为这是真的。我认为我们
we all are going to make sacrifices and
每个人都会在日常生活中做出牺牲和安排
priorities in our day and I think if you
优先事项。如果你
are saying you don't have enough time I
说你没有足够的时间，我
think there's ways to be strategic about
认为
how you manage your time in the day I
我们可以策略性地管理一天的时间。我
think we all have five minutes to
认为我们每个人都可以抽出五分钟来
implement a windown routine we can all
建立一个睡眠窗口，至少我们都可以
do that at the very least I think all of
做到这一点。我认为我们都可以
us can um optim ize our environment I
优化我们的环境，我们
think we all can invest in some sleep
可以投资一些助眠
tools I think we can make better choices
工具，我们可以更好地选择
about how you go about your day so you
如何度过一天，从而
set yourself up better for sleep so I
更好地为睡眠做好准备。我
think that those are just small
认为这些只是小小的
adjustments but will be huge in terms of
调整，但对
what that will mean at night um I hear
晚上睡眠的影响却非常大。嗯，我听说你会
sleep in the offseason right now in
在休赛期好好睡觉，现在
season is when I want to focus on being
赛季期间我想专注于发挥出
my best but really I think that's the a
最佳水平。但实际上，我认为
backwards way of thinking about it if
如果
you're thinking about optimizing your
你在
sleep when it gets to the season or the
赛季或
postseason when some of the most
季后赛期间才考虑优化睡眠，这是一种本末倒置的想法。 当一些最
important games come down the line
重要的比赛临近时，
you're just playing catchup because if
你往往只能疲于奔命。因为如果
you have a sleep that built up and
你之前睡眠不足，而
you're just trying to maintain that
你又试图在
through the season you actually are at a
整个赛季都保持这种状态，那么你实际上会
deficit versus the other guy or growl on
比队友或队友处于劣势，因为他们
the team who has paid that back in the
在
off seon now you have given yourself you
休赛期已经补足了睡眠，现在你
know zero sleep debt you're at your best
零睡眠债，处于最佳状态，
and now you're just trying to maintain
而你现在只是想在
that through the
整个
season what about injury what if I if
赛季都保持这种状态。那么受伤呢？如果
I'm an athlete and I'm underslept are
我是一名运动员，睡眠不足会怎样？是否
there any studies that suggest I'm more
有研究表明我更
prone to injury there are a few studies
容易受伤？有一些研究
that do suggest getting insufficient
确实表明
sleep so under 6 hours there's been more
睡眠不足（例如睡眠时间少于6小时）会增加
fatigue related injuries in adolescent
青少年运动员的疲劳相关损伤。
athletes there's also a study that has
还有一项研究表明，睡眠时间少于
looked at under eight hours of sleep
8小时
still has a increased risk around 1.7
仍然会增加受伤风险，大约是正常睡眠时间的1.7
fold higher of inj fold 170% yes yeah of
倍，也就是170%。是的，
getting under 8 hours of sleep versus
睡眠时间少于8小时的人比睡眠时间
those that got more than 8 hours of
超过8小时的人受伤风险更高。
sleep and so I think it's unclear
所以我认为目前还不清楚
exactly why you're specifically more at
为什么睡眠不足的人更
risk for injury but I tried to take a
容易受伤，但我尽力去寻找答案。 为了探究
what happens when athletes are not
运动员
getting sufficient sleep in one of my
睡眠不足时生物力学的变化，我
early studies um that has explored the
早期的一项研究就探讨了这个问题。研究表明，
is that when you're not getting
如果
sufficient sleep for multiple days you
连续几天睡眠不足，运动员的生物力学就会出现
have more more variability in your
更大的变异性。也就是说，他们的运动方式会发生变化，
selecting probably your preferred
可能无法选择他们偏好的
coordination strategy so for example I
协调策略。例如，我
had them doing a vertical jump and if
让他们进行垂直跳跃测试。如果
you're well rested you likely should be
休息充足，
elite athlete but when you're not well
精英运动员应该能够非常稳定地完成这项测试。但如果
rested it's much more variable so
休息不足，他们的运动方式就会出现很大的变异性，这
they're moving differently and that may
可能会增加
put people at risk for injury they like
受伤的风险。他们的
Landing differently a little bit jumping
落地方式和跳跃方式都会有所不同，
yeah how their knees their hips um are
膝盖和髋部的
coordinated together differs and so that
协调性也会发生变化。因此，这
may put you at risk for injury down the
可能会增加未来受伤的风险。
road but more to come hopefully on that
希望未来能有更多相关
front there's just not that many studies
研究。目前这方面的研究还不多。
that currently exist I've noticed
我
something recently because recently I've
最近注意到一些情况，因为最近我几次
had to get up quite early on a few occas
不得不很早起床。
so when I say early I mean I've had to
我说的早起是指我必须在凌晨三点就
go get wake up at 4:00 a.m. because I've
起床。 凌晨 4 点，因为我早上
got a flight at 6:00 a.m. and really
6 点有飞机。而且很
interestingly if I so say if I go in bed
有意思的是，如果我晚上
at like 11:00 p.m. at night and I and I
11 点就上床睡觉的话…… 晚上我睡得很晚，然后
have to wake up at say 3:00 or 4:00 a.m.
凌晨三四点就得起床。
when I wake up at 3:00 or 4 a.m. I'm
三四点醒来的时候我
really hungry but if I wake up at 8:00
特别饿，但如果早上八点醒来，我就不饿。这是因为
a.m. M I'm not hungry well you are
你
starting your day much earlier so your
一天开始得早了很多，所以你的
body clock is starting at a much earlier
生物钟启动的时间比平时早得多，而不是像平时那样从
8:00 so you almost have what we call
八点开始。这就好比你现在经历的“
socially jetlagged yourself right where
社交时差”，虽然
you didn't get on an airplane yet but
你还没坐飞机，但
you literally shifted your whole sleep
你实际上已经把整个睡眠
schedule to be an earlier wakeup time
时间都调整到了一个更早的起床时间。
and so you can feel some of the symptoms
所以你会感觉到一些时差反应的症状，比如
can have stomach GI upset you can feel
胃部不适、感觉
more fatigued you can have those
更疲惫等等，
symptoms as if you gotone onto a new
就像你飞到了一个新的
time zone and flew there but you hadn't
时区一样，但你实际上并没有飞过去。这种感觉
yet if it it almost feels dare I say
几乎就像是
like hormonal like it because I was
激素引起的，因为我一直在
trying to understand what hunger is and
试图理解饥饿是什么，而
hunger is essentially a bunch of
饥饿本质上是由多种
hormones isn't it so yes you have
激素引起的，不是吗？是的，有
certain hormones that regulate your
一些激素会调节你的
appetite so leptin and gin are two
食欲。 所以，瘦素和γ-谷氨酰tRNA是两种
hormones that impact your appetite um
影响食欲的激素。γ-
gin makes you more hungry leptin feels
谷氨酰tRNA会让你更饿，而瘦素会让你
more satiated if you don't get
更有饱腹感。如果
sufficient sleep these levels can be
睡眠不足，这两种激素的水平就会
imbalanced and so that's where people
失衡。这就是为什么我们之前讨论过，人们
gravitate towards you know carb and
往往会在傍晚时分偏爱碳水化合物和
unhealthy Foods in the later evening
不健康的食物。
time um but also when these are not well
但是，当这两种激素水平
balanced that can also lead to weight
失衡时，也会导致
gain or situations where you're not able
体重增加，或者无法
appropriately and so when I have
有效地控制体重。所以，当
individuals who are wondering about not
有人苦恼于无法
making weight goals I ask them about
达到减肥目标时，我会询问他们的
their sleep and they don't recognize
睡眠情况。他们往往没有意识到，
that sometimes being able to address how
改善
they sleep will actually help them to
睡眠实际上可以帮助他们
get to the weight management goals that
实现梦寐以求的体重管理目标。
they're really striving for Jack what
杰克，
about you we've talked about sleep
你呢？我们之前也聊过睡眠，
before how how are you sleeping at the
你现在的睡眠状况如何？我的
moment I've got pretty good at my sleep
睡眠质量还不错，
but waking up in the middle of the night
但是半夜会醒来。
you spoke about it in terms of like
你刚才提到过，
sleep happena but it feels like it
睡眠中醒来是正常的，但感觉
should be normal to wake up so
醒来应该是正常的。
Awakenings actually can be very normal
其实，半夜醒来
this is a very common question I get
是很正常的。 我经常
asked is you know should I never wake up
被问到的问题是，我晚上是不是绝对不能醒来？
at night and that's actually not true so
其实并非如此。
you shouldn't necessarily hit your head
你当然不应该一觉睡到天亮就一觉睡到天亮，完全
the full night and then never have an
不醒来。
Awakening if you wake up you go to the
如果你醒来
bathroom one time you come back fall
一次，去趟洗手间，回来后
asleep in the 5 to 10 minutes great
5到10分钟就能睡着，
that's actually very normal um so you
这其实很正常。你甚至会
in the early morning hours and that can
在清晨醒来，这
be just a typical part of your sleep
只是你睡眠
cycle because it can be as your
周期中正常的一部分。因为在不同的
transitioning between these sleep stages
睡眠阶段之间转换时，
that you'll have these Awakenings
你会经历这些醒来。
sometimes you'll consciously know that
有时你会意识到
you're awake and other times you will
自己醒了，有时则会无意识地
unconsciously awaken um and so something
醒来。像
like a wereable might actually show you
Wareable这样的设备可以显示你
that you have these Awakenings during
在
the night time that you don't recall um
夜间醒来但自己却不记得的情况。
but when it becomes very frequent then
但是，当这些醒来变得非常频繁，并且持续
multiple weeks or it makes it more
数周，或者让你的日常活动比白天更加
difficult and challenging than to
困难和具有挑战性时，
function in the daytime that's when we
我们
get more concerned about Awakenings
才会更加关注夜间醒来的问题。
why you can awaken at nighttime um to
导致夜间醒来的原因有很多，例如，
name a few it could be environmental
环境
factors that affect your sleep it could
因素会影响睡眠，
right before bedtime maybe there's
比如睡前饮酒，
caffeine that's causing you to be awake
咖啡因也可能让你保持清醒，
there's also just stress or if you just
压力过大或
have a racing mind that potentially
思绪纷乱都可能导致夜间醒来，
could cuse those Awakenings a bed
同床
partner is something that is a common
伴侣也是一个常见的
culprit um or underlying sleep apnea
诱因，此外，潜在的睡眠呼吸暂停也
that can happen and so there's early
可能导致夜间醒来。因此，
Awakenings that need to be investigated
早醒需要咨询
with your doctor how much does um
医生。
alcohol impact my sleep in percentage
酒精对睡眠的影响程度如何？
times I I don't know the specific
我不知道具体的统计
statistics of how that's going to impact
数据，
um um the the duration but I will say
但研究表明，
moderate to high consumption of alcohol
中度至重度饮酒与
more fragmented sleep more Awakenings
睡眠碎片化、
during the night time and so the quality
夜间醒来次数增多密切相关，
of your sleep is significantly impaired
睡眠质量也会显著下降。
so if you're trying to um have an
所以，如果你
important meeting the following day an
第二天要参加重要的会议、
important game or you're just trying to
比赛，或者只是想保持良好的睡眠状态，那么饮酒就显得尤为重要。
be able to be your best that following
第二天，你最好
day at least try to minimize or
尽量减少或
eliminate the alcohol or in the sleep in
完全戒酒。在
the sleep docks world we say drink when
睡眠领域，我们建议醒来后再喝酒，最好是
alcohol in the morning or the or the
在早上或
early afternoon not not necessarily
午后，而不是
right before bed and so um yeah that's
睡前。所以，嗯，是的，
sleeping Dr M we have a closing
睡前戒酒是其中一个策略。M博士，我们
tradition on this podcast where the last
这个播客有个结束的传统，上一位
guest leaves a question for the next
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个问题，但
guest not knowing who they're going to
不知道会是谁。留给
been left for you is if you could go
你的问题是：如果你可以回到过去，
back and fix your worst mistake but it
弥补你犯过的最糟糕的错误，但
would change everything afterwards with
之后的一切都会改变，而且
no
没有任何
guarantees would you do
保证，你会这么做吗？
it no I would not do it I think we make
不会。我认为
mistakes in life and we learn from them
人生中我们会犯错，我们会从中吸取教训，
and we adapt and we it can set us off in
我们会适应，这可能会让我们走上
a different direction but that
不同的道路，但
ultimately is going to influence who we
最终会影响我们
become who we interact with how we build
成为什么样的人，我们与谁互动，以及我们如何构建未来。
life life if I could go back and it
即使我可以回到过去，
could would set me on a completely
走上一条完全
different trajectory could you think of
不同的道路，我也不会改变我的人生。你能想到我犯过的
a worst mistake when I said that did one
最糟糕的错误吗？我说到这个话题时，你
come to mind or was that a category of
想到了一个吗？还是说这是一个类别？ 也许
there wasn't I maybe I haven't spent a
我没有花
lot of time to try and dive into some of
太多时间去深入剖析
my worst mistakes I definitely have made
我犯过的最严重的错误。当然，我
mistakes along the way and uh obviously
一路走来犯过不少错，而且很明显，
in my personal or professional life but
在我的个人生活或职业生涯中，有些事情我本可以做得更好。但
I do think that that is what has made me
我
who I am today right I think I have
认为正是这些错误造就了今天的我。我一直在
tried to learn from those mistakes
努力从这些错误中吸取教训，尽量
try not to make them again um and try to
避免重蹈覆辙，并努力找到应对之策。
that has I think set me on a path that
我认为正是这些错误把我引向了
uh is where I am today so I wouldn't I
今天的道路，所以我
wouldn't change that it's so interesting
不会改变。
the subject of sleep for me because I I
睡眠对我来说是一个非常有趣的话题，因为我曾经是“
was part of the like burnout Brigade The
倦怠大军”的一员，很
a long period of time and I I definitely
长一段时间都以“倦怠大军”为荣。
thought in my early career when I
在我职业生涯早期，
started my first business around 18 19
大约18、19、20、21岁开始创业，一直到
to say up until about 26
26岁左右，
I thought that me not sleeping was
我都觉得不睡觉是一种值得
something to show off and I thought that
炫耀的事情。我认为，
I was more impressive if I communicated
如果我告诉
to people how little I slept and how
别人我睡眠很少，却能
much I was able to accomplish in spite
完成这么多工作，我会显得更令人印象深刻。
of that I think actually the greatest en
尽管如此，我认为真正提升
enabler to my productivity is like being
我工作效率的最大助力是
really obsessive about my sleep and
极其重视睡眠，并
having that rule that I said where
坚持我之前定下的规矩：
nothing in my life unless there's a
除非是绝对不能耽搁的事情，否则我生活中的任何事情都不会
something that's immovable is booked
安排在上午
before 11 o00 and I really hope other
11点之前。我真心希望其他
people um after listening to you after
人，在听了你的分享，阅读了你
going through your work which is all
所有可以在
available online really prioritize their
网上找到的作品之后，也能真正重视
sleep because as you've shown through
睡眠。正如你通过
your research and the studies the the
研究和实验所展示的那样，睡眠
impact the very real impact on our lives
对我们生活的影响
is so profound maybe one shift in your
是如此深远，如此真实。或许你
mindset too that I encourage you but
也需要转变一下思维方式，我鼓励你，也鼓励
everyone that's listening as well is the
所有正在收听的人，就像
way I frame it to athletes is it's a
我跟运动员们解释的那样：睡眠只是一个
small tweak but if you think about sleep
小小的调整，但如果你把睡眠看作
is not the end of today it's the
是明天的开始，而不是今天的
beginning of tomorrow what you do to
结束，那么你为睡眠所做的
prepare
准备，
what you do to try and get the the
你为达到理想睡眠时
duration that you're striving for and
长所做的努力，以及
how you set yourself up will affect
你如何安排自己的作息，都会影响你的
everything about how you function how
一切，包括你的工作方式、
you interact with individuals and
你与他人的互动方式，以及
ultimately perform tomorrow if you're
最终你明天的表现。如果你
willing to do everything it takes for
愿意为了达到
you to be your best sleep has to be
最佳状态而付出一切，那么睡眠必须成为你
foundational in every day and if you're
每天的基础。如果你
willing to put in that time and that
愿意投入…… 投入时间和
effort you'll reap the benefits that
精力，你终将收获丰厚的回报，
come down the line and it can be
它甚至可以
completely
彻底
lifechanging but you have to give
改变你的人生。但你必须给予
yourself that Grace and that patience to
自己足够的宽容和耐心，才能
be able to make these small adjustments
做出这些小小的调整。正如
but as some of my athletes have shown it
我的一些运动员所展现的那样，这
can be a GameChanger for them it can
可以彻底改变他们的命运，一旦他们真正拥有高质量的睡眠，它就能
completely change the trajectory of
完全改变
their career and even life once they
他们的职业生涯乃至人生轨迹。
belt and so I challenge everyone to make
所以我鼓励大家从
small adjustments starting tonight and
今晚开始做出一些小小的调整。
reach out if you have questions but
如果你有任何疑问，欢迎随时联系我。那么，
where do we find you uh you can reach me
你可以通过以下方式联系我呢？你可以
at um Instagram Twitter or x uh Facebook
在Instagram、Twitter、Facebook或
um LinkedIn at Dr Sherry ma d r c h r i
LinkedIn上找到我，我的账号是Dr Sherry Ma d r c h r i
Mah or you can find me my website is Dr
Mah，或者访问我的网站Dr
sherim ma.com thank you so much I I know
sherim ma.com。非常感谢！我知道
that there's a lot of different
有很多
individuals from various sports teams
来自不同运动队的运动员都在
that listen because I speak to them I
关注我，因为我经常和他们交流。
Manchester United um two weeks ago in a
两周前，我在一家
hotel about from the well-being team
酒店里和曼联的一些健康团队成员谈论了
about these subjects and the sort of um
这些话题，以及
interconnected subjects of sleep and
睡眠和健康等相互关联的话题。此外，
well-being generally but also I've
我也和
spoken to people at Chelsea Football
切尔西的运动员交流过。 足球
Club that listen to the podcast about
俱乐部里有很多人都在听关于
these themes so I'm I'm convinced
这些主题的播客，所以我确信
there's going to be a lot of athletes
会有很多运动员
and aspiring athletes and just people
、有抱负的运动员，以及像我这样的人，都会
profoundly from the work that you do and
从你的工作和
the research that you've you've done
研究中受益匪浅。你的研究
that really shines the light on the
真正揭示了
importance of sleep which is often
睡眠的重要性，而睡眠常常被
misunderstood and is seen as a
误解，被视为
negotiable part of our lives so thank
生活中可以随意支配的一部分。
you so much for the work that you do and
非常感谢你的工作，
I'm very excited to see um where your
我非常期待看到你的
research and where your studies take you
研究和学习将你带向何方，
because it will be pioneering research
因为这必将是开创性的研究。
No Doubt thank you so much thanks for
毫无疑问，非常感谢，谢谢你们
having me it's been a
邀请我，这真是我的
pleasure perfect Ted has quite frankly
荣幸。坦白说，Perfect Ted已经
taken the nation by storm a small green
席卷全国，这是一种
energy drink that you've probably seen
你可能在Tesco或Waitrose超市见过的绿色能量饮料。
10,000% in a very short period of time
在很短的时间内，它的销量增长了近10000%，
because people are sick and tired of the
因为人们已经厌倦了那些
typical unhealthy energy drinks and
不健康的能量饮料，
they've been looking for an alternative
他们一直在寻找替代品。Perfect
perfect Ted is the drink that I drink as
Ted是我自己喝的饮料，因为
I'm sat here doing the podcast because
我…… 我坐在这里做播客，因为
it gives me increased focus it doesn't
它能让我更加专注，不会像
give me crashes which sometimes might
有时候那样，
happen if I'm having a three four five
如果我和播客嘉宾进行三四个五
six hour conversation with someone on
六个小时的对话，就会出现崩溃的情况。
the podcast and it tastes amazing it's
而且它的味道也棒极了，这正是
exactly what I've been looking for in
我一直在寻找的
terms of energy that's why I'm an
能量来源。这就是我成为
investor and that's why they sponsor
投资者的原因，也是他们赞助
this podcast and for a limited time
这个播客的原因。现在，
perfect Ted have given di of CEO
Perfect Ted 为 CEO 的
listeners only a huge 40% off if you use
听众们限时提供 40% 的折扣，只需
the code diary 40 at checkout don't tell
在结账时使用优惠码 diary40 即可。别告诉
anybody about this and you can only get
任何人，这个优惠仅限线上购买，而且
this online for limited time so make
时间有限，千万
sure you don't miss out
不要错过！
[Music]
[音乐]